<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>United States of America on Yﾄ》rﾄ［aya</title>
    <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/countries/united-states-of-america.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in United States of America on Yﾄ》rﾄ［aya</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2023 18:51:39 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/countries/united-states-of-america/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Yellowstone More to It Than Geysers</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/yellowstone-more-to-it-than-geysers.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2023 18:51:39 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/yellowstone-more-to-it-than-geysers.html</guid>
      <description>The friendly immigration officer was excited when I told him that I plan to visit Yellowstone National Park. He was from the same State, Wyoming. He said that if there was one place that one cannot really miss in the United States, it has got to be Yellowstone. I thanked him for his visa-stamping, generosity and his friendly advice. The drive from Salt Lake City to Jackson hole was through some of the most beautiful landscapes - vast areas of nothingness, beautiful rock formations and canyons in unbelievable shapes; everything in various shades of brown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Modest Trek Through a Grand Canyon</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/a-modest-trek-through-a-grand-canyon.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2023 18:43:05 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/a-modest-trek-through-a-grand-canyon.html</guid>
      <description>When someone I met recently was reciting the checklist of places he visited in the US and he mentioned New York, Vegas and Grand Canyon in one sentence, it disturbed me. He had achieved the feat of covering Grand Canyon within a day, from a helicopter, looking below. &amp;ldquo;Oh here&amp;rsquo;s the Grand Canyon. I&amp;rsquo;m done seeing it. Checked. Let&amp;rsquo;s move on&amp;rdquo;. I started thinking if that was possible at all for any place, let alone something as mammoth as the Grand Canyon, which has &amp;ldquo;grand&amp;rdquo; in its name itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Work Hard Beach Soft</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/work-hard-beach-soft.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 06:54:19 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/work-hard-beach-soft.html</guid>
      <description>As we drove farther to the west, the landscape changed from the usual staple of large buildings with their even-larger parking lots, to one, that in appearance, had a little more of what I conjure up in my mind whenever I come across the word &amp;lsquo;California&amp;rsquo;. A friend of mine had once told me I&amp;rsquo;d fit right in because I was a tree-hugger. In the literal sense of that term, at least, this seemed the most likely possibility as I witnessed here some of the largest, tallest and oldest redwood trees; trees whose circumference would have made me look like an insect hanging on to the bark when attempting to hug one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bryce : A Living Planetarium</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/bryce-a-living-planetarium.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2023 05:08:07 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/bryce-a-living-planetarium.html</guid>
      <description>It was not easy to comprehend the uniqueness of what was going on. There he was, a seemingly ordinary Park Ranger as he stood with his hands inside the pockets of his jacket to beat the chill of the night while he gave us a short lecture on what we were about to do and witness. I looked around. We were twenty of us who had signed up for the event, standing around in a circle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yellowstone where the Bisons still roam free</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/yellowstone-where-the-bisons-still-roam-free.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 22:13:30 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/yellowstone-where-the-bisons-still-roam-free.html</guid>
      <description>Vast stretches of grasslands till the horizon, spreading a greenish yellow carpet. The mountains far away decorate the edges of the grasslands. This land was owned by large herds of bison a long time ago till the western civilization set foot on the continent. The bison were bigger compared to their relatively smaller descendants we still see at Yellowstone today. The herds were larger too, of a scale that probably we might find it hard to imagine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Night at Southbeach Miami</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/a-night-at-southbeach-miami.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 22:09:04 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/a-night-at-southbeach-miami.html</guid>
      <description>It was our attempt to soak in as much Miami as we could in the short time we spent at South Beach. Night life at South Beach was exactly how I had visualized from my exposure to American films. It was all a grand party, a party that was on every night, without a break. So, we got ready to join this party, first as observers, from the periphery, then making our entry into this fantasy world of neon lights, loud Latino music, dance parties, speeding auto-mobiles and unlimited cocktails.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anchorage to Seward</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/anchorage-to-seward.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 05:03:21 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/anchorage-to-seward.html</guid>
      <description>There is something about trains that the moment someone mentions them, I get goosebumps; my heart starts racing and invariably. It is my wish to travel through some of the historical routes across the world, some spanning across continents and some meandering through unbelievable landscapes. I am always wondering about the ingenuity of the engineers who imagined a railroad and made it a reality. I try to incorporate train journeys to cover parts of my travel wherever feasible and affordable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talkeetna : Alaskan Hinterland</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/talkeetna-alaskan-hinterland.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 03:25:04 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/talkeetna-alaskan-hinterland.html</guid>
      <description>As I walked the barely asphalted road that led us from the well wooded section that closely guarded our hideout into what was the active and colourful part of the town, I started realizing why I liked this place so much. For one, it was unlike the rest of the United States. There was an authentic small-town feel to it. Not the sterile and templated small-town that one gets used to in the U.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Glacier Tour, Seward, Alaska</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/glacier-tour-seward.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2021 12:22:51 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/glacier-tour-seward.html</guid>
      <description>A bald eagle swooped in very close to our boat as we set off. The sun was struggling to shine through the dense grey clouds that threatened to pour down anytime. To be sailing off into the icy cold waters of the Pacific, with limited visibility, in the hope of seeing some glaciers, started to seem a bit ambitious. The misty cold morning confined most of us to the cozy interior of the boat, with little to look forward to other than this bald eagle and a friendly otter that did not seem to mind either our boat or the ice cold water.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Camping next to Savage river, Denali National Park</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/camping-at-savage-river.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 10:32:42 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/camping-at-savage-river.html</guid>
      <description>The weather was perfect when we entered Denali National Park. The sun was bright and our bus made a special stop on the way just for us to get a view of the majestic mountain Denali because it is not everyday that she presents herself in such glory. I have heard about the disappointment some people face when they spend two days at the National Park but fail to get a glimpse of the mountain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Denali at her raw best</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/denali-at-her-raw-best.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 10:17:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/denali-at-her-raw-best.html</guid>
      <description>Sitting in the park bus, I felt as though we were on a private tour of Denali National Park, just 4 of us, and our guide cum driver, Nick. It was to be the last trip for the day. That afternoon the entire Denali range was covered by thick clouds, it had started to get dark. Our chances of spotting wildlife also diminished with the daylight. With the rain looming in the horizon, we almost had the entire park for ourselves.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
