<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Train on Yﾄ》rﾄ［aya</title>
    <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/types/train.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Train on Yﾄ》rﾄ［aya</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 17:00:59 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/types/train/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Aboard the Madaraka Express from Mombasa to Nairobi, Kenya</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/mombasa-to-nairobi.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 17:00:59 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/mombasa-to-nairobi.html</guid>
      <description>East Africa is full of National Parks where some of the largest beasts to inhabit the earth, roam free. Sometimes, just sometimes, one gets to go through these national parks in a train. That is exactly what happened when we chose train as the mode of transport between Mombasa and Nairobi. The relatively new Standard Gauge Railway (SGR) that has been established between these two cities reaffirms the boundaries between Tsavo West and Tsavo East National Parks and is an experience that can be both unique and quite practical.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Descending the Himalayas in a Heritage Toy Train : Shimla to Kalka</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/descending-the-himalayas-heritage-toy-train.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 17:00:59 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/descending-the-himalayas-heritage-toy-train.html</guid>
      <description>The Shimla - Kalka Toy Train is hardly a realistic mode of transport today. A vestige of the colonial era, it only serves touristic value. But then again, we were tourists and we ought to behave like that. So we decided that it would be a worthy investment of our time to try out the journey in this colourful train that promises eye soothing views of the mountains and healthy mountain air for the lungs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anchorage to Seward</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/anchorage-to-seward.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 05:03:21 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/anchorage-to-seward.html</guid>
      <description>There is something about trains that the moment someone mentions them, I get goosebumps; my heart starts racing and invariably. It is my wish to travel through some of the historical routes across the world, some spanning across continents and some meandering through unbelievable landscapes. I am always wondering about the ingenuity of the engineers who imagined a railroad and made it a reality. I try to incorporate train journeys to cover parts of my travel wherever feasible and affordable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bentota to Colombo by train, Sri Lanka</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/bentota-to-colombo-train-srilanka.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jul 2021 20:23:18 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/bentota-to-colombo-train-srilanka.html</guid>
      <description>Local train journey in Sri Lanka is a must &amp;ldquo;to-do&amp;rdquo; to see the culture up close. And, what&amp;rsquo;s better than the coastal rail route that offers some breathtaking views of the coastline as well. Ours started at this quaint little station called Bentota.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
