<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Half Day on Yﾄ》rﾄ［aya</title>
    <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/duration/half-day.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Half Day on Yﾄ》rﾄ［aya</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 17:02:59 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/duration/half-day/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Chiang Mai, Thailand</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/exploring-chiang-mai-thailand.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 17:02:59 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/exploring-chiang-mai-thailand.html</guid>
      <description>For most people, Thailand is Bangkok and vis-a-vis. That included us too, until we had the opportunity to travel to Chiang Mai which happens to be an equally (if not more) important city in Thailand and has much to offer. We hardly had enough time to explore enough but these photographs are from one of the days we felt adventurous enough to venture into the busy city streets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aboard the Madaraka Express from Mombasa to Nairobi, Kenya</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/mombasa-to-nairobi.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 17:00:59 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/mombasa-to-nairobi.html</guid>
      <description>East Africa is full of National Parks where some of the largest beasts to inhabit the earth, roam free. Sometimes, just sometimes, one gets to go through these national parks in a train. That is exactly what happened when we chose train as the mode of transport between Mombasa and Nairobi. The relatively new Standard Gauge Railway (SGR) that has been established between these two cities reaffirms the boundaries between Tsavo West and Tsavo East National Parks and is an experience that can be both unique and quite practical.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Descending the Himalayas in a Heritage Toy Train : Shimla to Kalka</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/descending-the-himalayas-heritage-toy-train.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 17:00:59 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/descending-the-himalayas-heritage-toy-train.html</guid>
      <description>The Shimla - Kalka Toy Train is hardly a realistic mode of transport today. A vestige of the colonial era, it only serves touristic value. But then again, we were tourists and we ought to behave like that. So we decided that it would be a worthy investment of our time to try out the journey in this colourful train that promises eye soothing views of the mountains and healthy mountain air for the lungs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From the Bolivian Highlands of La Paz, to Copacabana</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/bus-ride-to-copacabana.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 17:00:59 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/bus-ride-to-copacabana.html</guid>
      <description>There are many ways to travel from La Paz, Bolivia to Cusco, Peru. What we chose to do was use the services of Bolivia Hop which is a hop-on-hop-off bus service that also had an optional stopover at Copacabana. These pictures tell the story of the first leg of that journey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High Altitude Capital City, La Paz, Bolivia</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/high-altitude-capital-city-la-paz.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 17:00:59 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/high-altitude-capital-city-la-paz.html</guid>
      <description>La Paz, the highest capital city in the world. What does it feel like? We knew very little, because we mostly used La Paz as a hop-off point for our trip to other seductive corners of Bolivia, but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t a wonder that we could relegate to the back-burner for long. So off we went on a short walk around the city to find out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Andaman Stargazing</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/andaman-stargazing.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2023 07:54:34 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/andaman-stargazing.html</guid>
      <description>I had this strange feeling of undeserved-ness when we sat there. My toes were digging into the sand into which a lot other tiny life forms were running into. The sea spoke with the same fervour, sometimes a little of it even caressing us as tiny droplets. It was just too good, just too real for it to be happening to us. The beach stretched miles to either side; usually we would be sharing it with a whole lot of humanity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dead Sea : World&#39;s Largest Outdoor Spa</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/dead-sea-worlds-largest-outdoor-spa.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2023 19:05:14 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/dead-sea-worlds-largest-outdoor-spa.html</guid>
      <description>You went to Jordan and you did not go to the Dead Sea? I did not want to hear this. Also I had heard so much about the Dead Sea in school. The Dead Sea is a unique place where the salt content is so high that you cannot sink. I had to experience this. On our last leg of journey from Wadi Rum to Madaba, we wanted to cover the Dead Sea.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Work Hard Beach Soft</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/work-hard-beach-soft.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 06:54:19 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/work-hard-beach-soft.html</guid>
      <description>As we drove farther to the west, the landscape changed from the usual staple of large buildings with their even-larger parking lots, to one, that in appearance, had a little more of what I conjure up in my mind whenever I come across the word &amp;lsquo;California&amp;rsquo;. A friend of mine had once told me I&amp;rsquo;d fit right in because I was a tree-hugger. In the literal sense of that term, at least, this seemed the most likely possibility as I witnessed here some of the largest, tallest and oldest redwood trees; trees whose circumference would have made me look like an insect hanging on to the bark when attempting to hug one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Land Border Crossing From Kenya to Uganda</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/land-border-crossing-from-kenya-to-uganda.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 06:07:37 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/land-border-crossing-from-kenya-to-uganda.html</guid>
      <description>They say, there is always a first time for everything. I remember some of my firsts and not all of them are pleasant ones. As the bus pulled up into a nondescript corner of the street and the conductor announced that we had arrived, I felt another first; anxious thoughts about the next few minutes. The last few hours were spent in the knowledge of what we were up to but anxiety had not taken over due to the novelty of what was on offer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Walking the Maara With the Masai</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/walking-the-maara-with-maasai.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 06:50:06 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/walking-the-maara-with-maasai.html</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Could you repeat that?&amp;rdquo; I asked.
&amp;ldquo;Born during the rains from Sangok,&amp;rdquo; he said.
He was taller than me but not so tall as to undeniably fit the bill as a typical Masai; anywhere between 35 and 40 years of age. He wore a traditional Masai outfit that betrayed a bit of its costume nature thanks to being prim, proper and perhaps ironed out. A day before that, during the drive here I had seen a few Masai villagers who walked the road, with dust that refused to part with their faces and clothes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bryce : A Living Planetarium</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/bryce-a-living-planetarium.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2023 05:08:07 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/bryce-a-living-planetarium.html</guid>
      <description>It was not easy to comprehend the uniqueness of what was going on. There he was, a seemingly ordinary Park Ranger as he stood with his hands inside the pockets of his jacket to beat the chill of the night while he gave us a short lecture on what we were about to do and witness. I looked around. We were twenty of us who had signed up for the event, standing around in a circle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Manali : Strangers Meet Like Friends</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/manali-strangers-meet-like-friends.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2023 13:49:29 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/manali-strangers-meet-like-friends.html</guid>
      <description>It wasn&amp;rsquo;t an unusual year by any standards. And if the changes in climate had already manifested into something palpable, then we did not know about it. We were three of us, and one of us was local.
&amp;ldquo;It should have snowed by now&amp;rdquo;, Brajesh said as he gestured us to pick up our two glasses of piping hot tea that were on a steel plate. He was already sipping his.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Amazonian Community of San Jose de Uchupiamonas</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/amazonian-community-of-san-jose-de-uchupiamonas.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 10:59:40 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/amazonian-community-of-san-jose-de-uchupiamonas.html</guid>
      <description>Very soon, the driver of our car sounded excited and stopped the car by the side of the road. Soon, we were all looking in the direction where he was looking. He had spotted some furry animals; extremely cute rodents. 5 or 6 young ones of the Capybara. The mother was nearby, quite large in comparison. Soon she and her flock disappeared into a burrow. This was our first sighting of Capybaras and we were extremely happy to see them from so near, just by the side of the road.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yellowstone where the Bisons still roam free</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/yellowstone-where-the-bisons-still-roam-free.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 22:13:30 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/yellowstone-where-the-bisons-still-roam-free.html</guid>
      <description>Vast stretches of grasslands till the horizon, spreading a greenish yellow carpet. The mountains far away decorate the edges of the grasslands. This land was owned by large herds of bison a long time ago till the western civilization set foot on the continent. The bison were bigger compared to their relatively smaller descendants we still see at Yellowstone today. The herds were larger too, of a scale that probably we might find it hard to imagine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Night at Southbeach Miami</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/a-night-at-southbeach-miami.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 22:09:04 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/a-night-at-southbeach-miami.html</guid>
      <description>It was our attempt to soak in as much Miami as we could in the short time we spent at South Beach. Night life at South Beach was exactly how I had visualized from my exposure to American films. It was all a grand party, a party that was on every night, without a break. So, we got ready to join this party, first as observers, from the periphery, then making our entry into this fantasy world of neon lights, loud Latino music, dance parties, speeding auto-mobiles and unlimited cocktails.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bonding with Boda Boda driver over football</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/bonding-with-bodaboda-driver-over-football.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 21:59:40 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/bonding-with-bodaboda-driver-over-football.html</guid>
      <description>Leaving Bwindi Impenetrable rainforests was quite painful. Very soon we would be pushed from pristine rainforests to flatlands in no time, and it also meant dealing with more people. I took in my last sights and smells to the fullest - the starlit sky, the fresh cool mountain air and the huge dark shadows in the backdrop of the mountains that were not yet visible before day break. We had to leave at 6am, which meant most of the work, like packing up our tent, having a good cup of morning coffee and saying goodbyes to our hosts had to be done in the cold and in darkness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drive Through Ishasha</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/drive-through-ishasha.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 21:59:40 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/drive-through-ishasha.html</guid>
      <description>On the streets of the small town Kihiihi, we sat found an empty taxi and quickly boarded it. As we had the breakfast that we had packed from Bwindi, we saw that the shops were just starting to open. We saw them getting ready for the day by arranging their display pieces outside and cleaning the entrances. There were many people all dressed up and purposeful, walking in a single direction and very excited.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Whirling Dervishes of Turkey</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/the-whirling-dervishes-of-turkey.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 21:52:04 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/the-whirling-dervishes-of-turkey.html</guid>
      <description>Istanbul&amp;rsquo;s reputation as a historical city with great culture and tradition was one of the reasons we decided to generously let it occupy a greater part of our Turkey trip. While reading about the culture, I came upon its Sufi tradition, known as the Mevlevi Order; inspired by &amp;ldquo;Mevlana&amp;rdquo; Rumi, the famous Islamic mystical poet and spiritual master. Sufism is a form of Islam which emphasizes the inward search for God through direct connect and promotes realization of God through love and music.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indigo Dyeing : Phrae, Thailand</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/indigo-dyeing-phrae-thailand.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 21:41:29 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/indigo-dyeing-phrae-thailand.html</guid>
      <description>The various shades of blue on either side of the main road told us that we had reached our destination - Ban Thung Hong, the Blue Village as it is popularly known. A group of six friends with a shared passion for indigo, we had set out to explore the source of this beautiful colour. True to its name, this quaint village, just outside the city of Phrae is a relic from the Kingdom of Old Siam.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Land Border Crossing from Kenya to Tanzania</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/land-border-crossing-from-kenya-to-tanzania.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 21:31:49 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/land-border-crossing-from-kenya-to-tanzania.html</guid>
      <description>We left Kisii early in the morning, after a breakfast consisting of coffee and Mandazi. The Matatu stand was close to where we stayed and this gave us the advantage of walking right up to it with our backpacks. As expected, someone &amp;ldquo;fished&amp;rdquo; us and led us through the maze of Matatus parked to a specific one that said Kisii Direct. We had learned that &amp;ldquo;direct&amp;rdquo; means no changes/transfers midway. Then again, we knew enough by now - practical and experienced in this part of the world - that what they promised was not always what they delivered.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life in Spiti</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/life-in-spiti.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 21:22:41 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/life-in-spiti.html</guid>
      <description>I sat there as though in a trance; watching how the horizontal yarn moved through the hundreds of threads that were hanging along the frame of the loom. Her hands moving rhythmically in a quick, yet, skilful way made me wonder how it might feel to sit there in solitude, patiently working on the pattern. It was meditative. I had a hundred questions to ask her. I hesitated. Would she get disturbed by my interruption and make a mistake?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Babbling on a clothesline</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/babbling-on-a-clothesline.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 06:46:36 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/babbling-on-a-clothesline.html</guid>
      <description>A wet babbler jumped up on a clothesline under a shelter to escape the downpour. A moment ago she was busy pecking on the wet ground in search of insects and worms. With no sunshine the entire morning, birds were not at their chirpy best, they must be going through their mood swings too! The overcast skies covered everything in dull grey. The babblers still needed to look for their food.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Nairobi to Narok</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/from-nairobi-to-narok.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 06:25:47 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/from-nairobi-to-narok.html</guid>
      <description>The notorious reputation of Matatus that I had gathered from various forums preceded their appearance. This made me look at each of them with horror, like they were assassins. When I saw them while crossing the street, I would jump and step back, holding my partner&amp;rsquo;s hand tightly, with my eyes shut, as though, they were on a mission to kill; as if they would, at any time, veer off the road, into the footpath and run me over.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parque Arvi : Nature overlooking Medellin</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/parque-arvi-nature-overlooking-medellin.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 06:04:48 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/parque-arvi-nature-overlooking-medellin.html</guid>
      <description>Lucky are the people of Medellin that just an hour away from the busy city is one of the most beautiful parks that has not just breathtaking scenery but also some amazing biodiversity. When we ended up a whole day late in Medellin, at night, after our harrowing flight without our bags, little did I know that the misfortunes we faced the previous day would be compensated manifold by allowing us an extra day in the city that was not earlier planned.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tallest Palm in the World</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/tallest-palm-in-the-world.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 05:47:40 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/tallest-palm-in-the-world.html</guid>
      <description>I looked up a slender tree right in front of me, I lifted my head up and up, bent backwards as far as I could balance, but failed to see the crown. The morning sun was filtering through the scant crown of the giant palms blinding me as I squinted to gauge the full extent of its height. What seemed like a regular palm tree from a distance, unimpressive at a first glance, grew to unbelievable height as I approached it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trip to a Bolivian Consulate</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/trip-to-a-bolivian-consulate.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 05:30:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/trip-to-a-bolivian-consulate.html</guid>
      <description>Most of the tourists who land at the Calama Airport in Northern Chile have but one purpose which is to book a direct taxi to their real destination, San Pedro de Atacama, the jewel of the Atacama desert, a picturesque town that is tailored around tourism. Calama, on the other hand is a mining town visited by workers - both short and long term - and people who have some business connected to mining.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We still have not seen the Tapir</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/we-still-have-not-seen-the-tapir.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 05:11:21 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/we-still-have-not-seen-the-tapir.html</guid>
      <description>At 4am, I could see the faint light in the other tents. Braving the cold and in complete darkness with the help of a flash-light, I managed to crawl out of mine. The moonless sky shone with a million stars. Wearing our rubber boots our team of four started walking towards the forest. The cicadas seemed to cheer us on and follow us into the darkness as we moved in. The eerie ambience was complemented by a million other insects that were probably protesting as we walked through the maze of branches and roots.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anchorage to Seward</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/anchorage-to-seward.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 05:03:21 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/anchorage-to-seward.html</guid>
      <description>There is something about trains that the moment someone mentions them, I get goosebumps; my heart starts racing and invariably. It is my wish to travel through some of the historical routes across the world, some spanning across continents and some meandering through unbelievable landscapes. I am always wondering about the ingenuity of the engineers who imagined a railroad and made it a reality. I try to incorporate train journeys to cover parts of my travel wherever feasible and affordable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talkeetna : Alaskan Hinterland</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/talkeetna-alaskan-hinterland.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 03:25:04 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/talkeetna-alaskan-hinterland.html</guid>
      <description>As I walked the barely asphalted road that led us from the well wooded section that closely guarded our hideout into what was the active and colourful part of the town, I started realizing why I liked this place so much. For one, it was unlike the rest of the United States. There was an authentic small-town feel to it. Not the sterile and templated small-town that one gets used to in the U.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Turkish Bath at a Hamam, Istanbul</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/hamam-at-istanbul-turkey.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 19:55:03 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/hamam-at-istanbul-turkey.html</guid>
      <description>After having spent two months backpacking and camping, the idea of a nice hot Turkish bath seemed most desirable. Although I did not have a first hand experience about a Hamam, having read a few blogs about it, I felt I was bold enough to give it a try. Having been to Istanbul and not trying the Hamam was not acceptable for me. I kept putting it off for the first couple of days, with certain inhibitions getting the better of my cravings for a hot bath.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azaan at Sultanahmet, Istanbul</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/azaan-at-sultanahmet-istanbul.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 18:58:38 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/azaan-at-sultanahmet-istanbul.html</guid>
      <description>Walking the crowded streets of Sultanahmet late evening, I was trying to negotiate a road crossing, just as a tram passed the street. The wind was chill yet filled with the aroma of the food from the roadside restaurants. Just then, I heard the most melodious tune somewhere far that made me freeze. I just stood there mesmerized, holding on to every single sound that came out from this singer. The words &amp;ldquo;Allahu Akhbar&amp;rdquo;, probably heard several times in my lifetime, had never before sounded so beautiful, so profound.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bentota to Colombo by train, Sri Lanka</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/bentota-to-colombo-train-srilanka.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jul 2021 20:23:18 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/bentota-to-colombo-train-srilanka.html</guid>
      <description>Local train journey in Sri Lanka is a must &amp;ldquo;to-do&amp;rdquo; to see the culture up close. And, what&amp;rsquo;s better than the coastal rail route that offers some breathtaking views of the coastline as well. Ours started at this quaint little station called Bentota.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Glacier Tour, Seward, Alaska</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/glacier-tour-seward.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2021 12:22:51 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/glacier-tour-seward.html</guid>
      <description>A bald eagle swooped in very close to our boat as we set off. The sun was struggling to shine through the dense grey clouds that threatened to pour down anytime. To be sailing off into the icy cold waters of the Pacific, with limited visibility, in the hope of seeing some glaciers, started to seem a bit ambitious. The misty cold morning confined most of us to the cozy interior of the boat, with little to look forward to other than this bald eagle and a friendly otter that did not seem to mind either our boat or the ice cold water.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When the entire village came dressed in their finery</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/entire-village-finery.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2020 16:16:02 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/entire-village-finery.html</guid>
      <description>We decided to visit the Kibber Gompa on a day when we heard there was an important event. Not knowing what it was about, we went along, with our camera ready. We were surprised to find almost the entire village there, young and the old, with more joining in. There was an air of festivity and cheer. Not knowing the language, we smiled at whoever our eyes met with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whale Watching at Mirissa, Sri Lanka</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/whale-watching-lanka.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 17:13:01 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/whale-watching-lanka.html</guid>
      <description>This was nothing close to what I had imagined. The boat was rather small. The waves were menacingly rough, and threatened to throw the boat off balance at the slightest opportunity. There were about 20 people on the boat, most of them in various stages of sea sickness. The lucky ones, like myself, who were miraculously unaffected by the rough sea, were on the deck with our eyes glued to the waters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Live Music Bar at Goreme, Cappadocia, Turkey</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/live-music-bar-goreme.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 16:57:03 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/live-music-bar-goreme.html</guid>
      <description>The cold air was broken by the white trail of warm breath as I walked into the night. The bar was just a block away from where we stayed. The tables were only beginning to be occupied. We asked for a table for two, ordered some Raki that came with some soft bread and dips. The lights were dim and created a warm and cozy atmosphere. Everyone were dressed in party-wear, colourful, resplendent with makeup and jewellery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An unforgettable encounter with our closest cousin</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/our-closest-cousin.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2019 19:17:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/our-closest-cousin.html</guid>
      <description>It was unmistakably the most beautiful place we would be staying in our entire trip. I could spend hours just looking at the mountains, and the rainforests and never cease to be amazed by their existence, being drawn into them further and further with every passing moment. I could be lost momentarily in mundane tasks like eating or washing clothes or fussing about the ants but the presence of the mountains constantly pulls me into a trance every now and then.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Andaman Forest Walk</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/andaman-forest-walk.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 12:31:29 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/andaman-forest-walk.html</guid>
      <description>Neil Island, being one of the smaller ones of the Andaman archipelago, is an inconspicuous dot in the vast blue waters of the mighty Indian Ocean. Here one gets the sensation of being &amp;lsquo;bound&amp;rsquo; or &amp;rsquo;limited&amp;rsquo; by the land area. Getting to experience both sunrise and sunset on the same day was something that I looked forward to on small islands and Neil had not disappointed me in that respect. In just a couple of days of arriving on Neil Island, I got the feeling that we had already explored everything there was worth exploring.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
