<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mountain on Yﾄ》rﾄ［aya</title>
    <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/types/mountain.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mountain on Yﾄ》rﾄ［aya</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 07:35:05 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/types/mountain/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Keylong : A Few Days before Cut-Off</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/keylong-a-few-days-before-cut-off.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 07:35:05 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/keylong-a-few-days-before-cut-off.html</guid>
      <description>We were on our way down from Shasur Gompa. The Gompa visit was a self-guided tour and hence it was limited to looking around at flags, murals and ubiquitous style and architecture that we had seen before and making up our own stories and assumptions. But I was sure we missed a lot. There must have been a larger history and then a local history. There must have been some drama and a legend and a myth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Short Trek to a Lake in the Sky</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/a-short-trek-to-a-lake-in-the-sky.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 06:08:21 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/a-short-trek-to-a-lake-in-the-sky.html</guid>
      <description>Our host, over evening cup of hot tea mentioned about the Dhankar lake that was a must visit. I was happy that there were not many guests either at our homestay or any other around, which meant that there would be lesser crowds at the lake the next morning. Our host offered to pack us Aloo Paranthas to carry on our little expedition. We started off on a trail from Dhankar Gompa that would take us further higher by another 200-300 metres, to this high altitude lake at 4150 meters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Trek to Kuari Pass and Pangarchulla, Uttarakhand</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/trek-to-kuari-pass-pangarchulla.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2019 19:32:50 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/trek-to-kuari-pass-pangarchulla.html</guid>
      <description>My back was unaccustomed to the heavy load. It was more than a year since I had been on any serious multi-day hike. And, even though we had hired a couple of porters and a guide to carry the camping equipment and the cooking essentials, even the personal items that I had signed up to haul was seeming heavier than I had imagined. The moment I got out of the jeep and started walking through the narrow lanes of the village Dhak, two thoughts were on my mind.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
