<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kenya on Yﾄ》rﾄ［aya</title>
    <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/countries/kenya.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Kenya on Yﾄ》rﾄ［aya</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 17:00:59 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/countries/kenya/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Aboard the Madaraka Express from Mombasa to Nairobi, Kenya</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/mombasa-to-nairobi.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 17:00:59 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/mombasa-to-nairobi.html</guid>
      <description>East Africa is full of National Parks where some of the largest beasts to inhabit the earth, roam free. Sometimes, just sometimes, one gets to go through these national parks in a train. That is exactly what happened when we chose train as the mode of transport between Mombasa and Nairobi. The relatively new Standard Gauge Railway (SGR) that has been established between these two cities reaffirms the boundaries between Tsavo West and Tsavo East National Parks and is an experience that can be both unique and quite practical.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Land Border Crossing From Kenya to Uganda</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/land-border-crossing-from-kenya-to-uganda.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 06:07:37 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/land-border-crossing-from-kenya-to-uganda.html</guid>
      <description>They say, there is always a first time for everything. I remember some of my firsts and not all of them are pleasant ones. As the bus pulled up into a nondescript corner of the street and the conductor announced that we had arrived, I felt another first; anxious thoughts about the next few minutes. The last few hours were spent in the knowledge of what we were up to but anxiety had not taken over due to the novelty of what was on offer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Walking the Maara With the Masai</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/walking-the-maara-with-maasai.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 06:50:06 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/walking-the-maara-with-maasai.html</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Could you repeat that?&amp;rdquo; I asked.
&amp;ldquo;Born during the rains from Sangok,&amp;rdquo; he said.
He was taller than me but not so tall as to undeniably fit the bill as a typical Masai; anywhere between 35 and 40 years of age. He wore a traditional Masai outfit that betrayed a bit of its costume nature thanks to being prim, proper and perhaps ironed out. A day before that, during the drive here I had seen a few Masai villagers who walked the road, with dust that refused to part with their faces and clothes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Land Border Crossing from Kenya to Tanzania</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/land-border-crossing-from-kenya-to-tanzania.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 21:31:49 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/land-border-crossing-from-kenya-to-tanzania.html</guid>
      <description>We left Kisii early in the morning, after a breakfast consisting of coffee and Mandazi. The Matatu stand was close to where we stayed and this gave us the advantage of walking right up to it with our backpacks. As expected, someone &amp;ldquo;fished&amp;rdquo; us and led us through the maze of Matatus parked to a specific one that said Kisii Direct. We had learned that &amp;ldquo;direct&amp;rdquo; means no changes/transfers midway. Then again, we knew enough by now - practical and experienced in this part of the world - that what they promised was not always what they delivered.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Nairobi to Narok</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/from-nairobi-to-narok.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 06:25:47 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/from-nairobi-to-narok.html</guid>
      <description>The notorious reputation of Matatus that I had gathered from various forums preceded their appearance. This made me look at each of them with horror, like they were assassins. When I saw them while crossing the street, I would jump and step back, holding my partner&amp;rsquo;s hand tightly, with my eyes shut, as though, they were on a mission to kill; as if they would, at any time, veer off the road, into the footpath and run me over.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
