<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Full Day on Yﾄ》rﾄ［aya</title>
    <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/duration/full-day.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Full Day on Yﾄ》rﾄ［aya</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 21:56:24 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/duration/full-day/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Moving With the Mail</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/moving-with-the-mail.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 21:56:24 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/moving-with-the-mail.html</guid>
      <description>I had read about the post bus: a bus service run by the postal department of Uganda. However, nothing that I had read would prepare us for what we were about to go through. At 4:30am, lugging our heavy backpacks, we undertook a short, yet scary walk through the roads of Kampala to reach the post office. In most parts of Uganda, especially in busy market areas of down-town Kampala, where we stayed, near the bus stand, we were afraid of getting mugged while walking in the darkness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day trip to Playa Blanca, Colombia</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/day-trip-to-playa-blanca-colombia.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 05:57:05 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/day-trip-to-playa-blanca-colombia.html</guid>
      <description>The thought of white sandy beaches with blue waters felt almost too good to be true. Tourists mostly head to Cartagena to experience exactly this. The Caribbean islands are famous for some of the most pristine and picturesque beaches in the world. We were surprisingly one of the few who were in Cartagena without a clear intention of soaking in the sun on one of these beaches. Reluctantly, one morning, we walked to one of the hostels which was arranging day tours to Playa Blanca, which, in Spanish, simply means the White Beach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No one can stop looking at Jardin</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/no-one-can-stop-looking-at-jardin.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 05:42:29 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/no-one-can-stop-looking-at-jardin.html</guid>
      <description>I have many a times sifted through my memories to focus on the colourful postcards in my mind&amp;rsquo;s eye that for me represent Jardin, and I have wondered, what was it that I did there for a couple of days? As simple as it might sound, nothing really. Absolutely nothing if I were to be accurate. Yes. If there is a really good venue for doing nothing, then it had to be Jardin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lounge-birding at Sadiri lodge</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/lounge-birding-at-sadiri-lodge.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 05:24:31 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/lounge-birding-at-sadiri-lodge.html</guid>
      <description>We got a glimpse of what we would experience after 3 days when we stepped into Sadiri Lodge briefly to put away some our clothes that we wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be needing during the camping. The lodge was located on a hill, the steep slope of which was lined with a stone-pitched stairway that we arduously climbed. The entrance of the prominent looking building, completely built of wood, led to the dining hall with a large balcony overlooking the dramatic mountain ranges of Amazon rainforests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A walk through Sinharaja Forest Reserve, Sri Lanka</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/sinharaja-forest-reserve-srilanka.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 19:33:32 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/sinharaja-forest-reserve-srilanka.html</guid>
      <description>I had imagined this tear-drop-shaped island country always to have been green; a green dot floating in the endless blue waters of the mighty Indian Ocean. I would like to believe that it was once covered with dense impenetrable tropical rainforests, with innumerable waterfalls and countless streams. It was perhaps my effort to recreate this lost experience, when I chose trekking through the Sinharaja Forest Reserve as one of my first experiences in Sri Lanka.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Denali at her raw best</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/denali-at-her-raw-best.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 10:17:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/denali-at-her-raw-best.html</guid>
      <description>Sitting in the park bus, I felt as though we were on a private tour of Denali National Park, just 4 of us, and our guide cum driver, Nick. It was to be the last trip for the day. That afternoon the entire Denali range was covered by thick clouds, it had started to get dark. Our chances of spotting wildlife also diminished with the daylight. With the rain looming in the horizon, we almost had the entire park for ourselves.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
