<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Asia on Yﾄ》rﾄ［aya</title>
    <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/continents/asia.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Asia on Yﾄ》rﾄ［aya</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2023 07:54:34 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/continents/asia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Andaman Stargazing</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/andaman-stargazing.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2023 07:54:34 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/andaman-stargazing.html</guid>
      <description>I had this strange feeling of undeserved-ness when we sat there. My toes were digging into the sand into which a lot other tiny life forms were running into. The sea spoke with the same fervour, sometimes a little of it even caressing us as tiny droplets. It was just too good, just too real for it to be happening to us. The beach stretched miles to either side; usually we would be sharing it with a whole lot of humanity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dead Sea : World&#39;s Largest Outdoor Spa</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/dead-sea-worlds-largest-outdoor-spa.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2023 19:05:14 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/dead-sea-worlds-largest-outdoor-spa.html</guid>
      <description>You went to Jordan and you did not go to the Dead Sea? I did not want to hear this. Also I had heard so much about the Dead Sea in school. The Dead Sea is a unique place where the salt content is so high that you cannot sink. I had to experience this. On our last leg of journey from Wadi Rum to Madaba, we wanted to cover the Dead Sea.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Improbability of Castle Rock</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/the-improbability-of-castle-rock.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2023 08:43:33 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/the-improbability-of-castle-rock.html</guid>
      <description>Technically, Castlerock is only half a day away from some of the largest cities and innumerable towns of North Karnataka. For that matter, this little village (to use the official term for the place), is only a stone&amp;rsquo;s throw away from the touristy destinations such as Goa. But technicalities do not matter, because despite its long history, Castlerock seems to insist on folding itself away into a corner of the Western Ghats, mostly untouched by whatever is happening a few 100 kilometres around.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keylong : A Few Days before Cut-Off</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/keylong-a-few-days-before-cut-off.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 07:35:05 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/keylong-a-few-days-before-cut-off.html</guid>
      <description>We were on our way down from Shasur Gompa. The Gompa visit was a self-guided tour and hence it was limited to looking around at flags, murals and ubiquitous style and architecture that we had seen before and making up our own stories and assumptions. But I was sure we missed a lot. There must have been a larger history and then a local history. There must have been some drama and a legend and a myth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Short Trek to a Lake in the Sky</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/a-short-trek-to-a-lake-in-the-sky.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 06:08:21 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/a-short-trek-to-a-lake-in-the-sky.html</guid>
      <description>Our host, over evening cup of hot tea mentioned about the Dhankar lake that was a must visit. I was happy that there were not many guests either at our homestay or any other around, which meant that there would be lesser crowds at the lake the next morning. Our host offered to pack us Aloo Paranthas to carry on our little expedition. We started off on a trail from Dhankar Gompa that would take us further higher by another 200-300 metres, to this high altitude lake at 4150 meters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Manali : Strangers Meet Like Friends</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/manali-strangers-meet-like-friends.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2023 13:49:29 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/manali-strangers-meet-like-friends.html</guid>
      <description>It wasn&amp;rsquo;t an unusual year by any standards. And if the changes in climate had already manifested into something palpable, then we did not know about it. We were three of us, and one of us was local.
&amp;ldquo;It should have snowed by now&amp;rdquo;, Brajesh said as he gestured us to pick up our two glasses of piping hot tea that were on a steel plate. He was already sipping his.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bulbuls in my backyard</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/bulbuls-in-my-backyard.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 18:57:57 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/bulbuls-in-my-backyard.html</guid>
      <description>When a bulbul pair visits your backyard frequently, converse with each other incessantly, you get the feeling that you are about to witness something exciting. The fact that this was happening during a time when I apparently had a lot of free time to sit and take note of my surroundings was serendipitous. I decided to keep my camera handy. Although I try to take an observant position consciously, the animal rehabilitator in me compels me to intervene; especially when I saw that they had very carefully chosen the thin intersection of the clothesline and the overhead rod to start building their nest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Whirling Dervishes of Turkey</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/the-whirling-dervishes-of-turkey.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 21:52:04 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/the-whirling-dervishes-of-turkey.html</guid>
      <description>Istanbul&amp;rsquo;s reputation as a historical city with great culture and tradition was one of the reasons we decided to generously let it occupy a greater part of our Turkey trip. While reading about the culture, I came upon its Sufi tradition, known as the Mevlevi Order; inspired by &amp;ldquo;Mevlana&amp;rdquo; Rumi, the famous Islamic mystical poet and spiritual master. Sufism is a form of Islam which emphasizes the inward search for God through direct connect and promotes realization of God through love and music.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life in Spiti</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/life-in-spiti.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 21:22:41 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/life-in-spiti.html</guid>
      <description>I sat there as though in a trance; watching how the horizontal yarn moved through the hundreds of threads that were hanging along the frame of the loom. Her hands moving rhythmically in a quick, yet, skilful way made me wonder how it might feel to sit there in solitude, patiently working on the pattern. It was meditative. I had a hundred questions to ask her. I hesitated. Would she get disturbed by my interruption and make a mistake?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Babbling on a clothesline</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/babbling-on-a-clothesline.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 06:46:36 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/babbling-on-a-clothesline.html</guid>
      <description>A wet babbler jumped up on a clothesline under a shelter to escape the downpour. A moment ago she was busy pecking on the wet ground in search of insects and worms. With no sunshine the entire morning, birds were not at their chirpy best, they must be going through their mood swings too! The overcast skies covered everything in dull grey. The babblers still needed to look for their food.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It is raining in Kerala!</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/rains-kerala.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 06:39:29 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/rains-kerala.html</guid>
      <description>The leaves are bright green of various shades, all washed and cleaned. Everything turns green - the plants, trees, walls, the floor, there is fresh growth all around. The trees and plants have all drank to their fill and stored up water for the next season. The soil has soaked up water and is saturated. Small streams of brown water are making their way through previously non-existent routes to lower lands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Turkish Bath at a Hamam, Istanbul</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/hamam-at-istanbul-turkey.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 19:55:03 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/hamam-at-istanbul-turkey.html</guid>
      <description>After having spent two months backpacking and camping, the idea of a nice hot Turkish bath seemed most desirable. Although I did not have a first hand experience about a Hamam, having read a few blogs about it, I felt I was bold enough to give it a try. Having been to Istanbul and not trying the Hamam was not acceptable for me. I kept putting it off for the first couple of days, with certain inhibitions getting the better of my cravings for a hot bath.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Staying in a cavehouse at Goreme, Cappadocia</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/goreme-cappadocia-homestay.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 19:32:07 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/goreme-cappadocia-homestay.html</guid>
      <description>Goreme was a beautiful town in a valley beyond the vast, brown mountains and large smooth rocks that resembled endless mounds of mud. That morning, we were transferred to a mini-bus after an overnight journey in a comfortable, large bus. We had got used to the efficiency of this country, and the general goodness of people, so we only had to step out of the bus and step into the smaller bus, without having to fuss about our luggages, which were perfectly tagged and transferred promptly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azaan at Sultanahmet, Istanbul</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/azaan-at-sultanahmet-istanbul.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 18:58:38 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/azaan-at-sultanahmet-istanbul.html</guid>
      <description>Walking the crowded streets of Sultanahmet late evening, I was trying to negotiate a road crossing, just as a tram passed the street. The wind was chill yet filled with the aroma of the food from the roadside restaurants. Just then, I heard the most melodious tune somewhere far that made me freeze. I just stood there mesmerized, holding on to every single sound that came out from this singer. The words &amp;ldquo;Allahu Akhbar&amp;rdquo;, probably heard several times in my lifetime, had never before sounded so beautiful, so profound.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A walk through Sinharaja Forest Reserve, Sri Lanka</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/sinharaja-forest-reserve-srilanka.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 19:33:32 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/sinharaja-forest-reserve-srilanka.html</guid>
      <description>I had imagined this tear-drop-shaped island country always to have been green; a green dot floating in the endless blue waters of the mighty Indian Ocean. I would like to believe that it was once covered with dense impenetrable tropical rainforests, with innumerable waterfalls and countless streams. It was perhaps my effort to recreate this lost experience, when I chose trekking through the Sinharaja Forest Reserve as one of my first experiences in Sri Lanka.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whale Watching at Mirissa, Sri Lanka</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/whale-watching-lanka.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 17:13:01 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/whale-watching-lanka.html</guid>
      <description>This was nothing close to what I had imagined. The boat was rather small. The waves were menacingly rough, and threatened to throw the boat off balance at the slightest opportunity. There were about 20 people on the boat, most of them in various stages of sea sickness. The lucky ones, like myself, who were miraculously unaffected by the rough sea, were on the deck with our eyes glued to the waters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Live Music Bar at Goreme, Cappadocia, Turkey</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/live-music-bar-goreme.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 16:57:03 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/live-music-bar-goreme.html</guid>
      <description>The cold air was broken by the white trail of warm breath as I walked into the night. The bar was just a block away from where we stayed. The tables were only beginning to be occupied. We asked for a table for two, ordered some Raki that came with some soft bread and dips. The lights were dim and created a warm and cozy atmosphere. Everyone were dressed in party-wear, colourful, resplendent with makeup and jewellery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Words cannot describe vibes, Arambol, Goa</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/return-to-arambol-goa.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 16:57:03 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/return-to-arambol-goa.html</guid>
      <description>On our very first trip to Goa, the mystical beach of Arambol was but a short two hour visit; an interlude between the many places we visited. Back then, it was sort of an insatiable hunger, perhaps greed even to &amp;ldquo;see it all&amp;rdquo;. It was a ride on a ramshackle rented bike from Vagator - where we were shacked up; an evening ride got us there just in time for a spectacular sunset at the Arambol beach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Trek to Kuari Pass and Pangarchulla, Uttarakhand</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/trek-to-kuari-pass-pangarchulla.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2019 19:32:50 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/trek-to-kuari-pass-pangarchulla.html</guid>
      <description>My back was unaccustomed to the heavy load. It was more than a year since I had been on any serious multi-day hike. And, even though we had hired a couple of porters and a guide to carry the camping equipment and the cooking essentials, even the personal items that I had signed up to haul was seeming heavier than I had imagined. The moment I got out of the jeep and started walking through the narrow lanes of the village Dhak, two thoughts were on my mind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Andaman Forest Walk</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/andaman-forest-walk.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 12:31:29 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/andaman-forest-walk.html</guid>
      <description>Neil Island, being one of the smaller ones of the Andaman archipelago, is an inconspicuous dot in the vast blue waters of the mighty Indian Ocean. Here one gets the sensation of being &amp;lsquo;bound&amp;rsquo; or &amp;rsquo;limited&amp;rsquo; by the land area. Getting to experience both sunrise and sunset on the same day was something that I looked forward to on small islands and Neil had not disappointed me in that respect. In just a couple of days of arriving on Neil Island, I got the feeling that we had already explored everything there was worth exploring.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
