<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nature on Yﾄ》rﾄ［aya</title>
    <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/types/nature.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Nature on Yﾄ》rﾄ［aya</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2023 07:54:34 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/types/nature/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Andaman Stargazing</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/andaman-stargazing.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2023 07:54:34 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/andaman-stargazing.html</guid>
      <description>I had this strange feeling of undeserved-ness when we sat there. My toes were digging into the sand into which a lot other tiny life forms were running into. The sea spoke with the same fervour, sometimes a little of it even caressing us as tiny droplets. It was just too good, just too real for it to be happening to us. The beach stretched miles to either side; usually we would be sharing it with a whole lot of humanity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dead Sea : World&#39;s Largest Outdoor Spa</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/dead-sea-worlds-largest-outdoor-spa.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2023 19:05:14 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/dead-sea-worlds-largest-outdoor-spa.html</guid>
      <description>You went to Jordan and you did not go to the Dead Sea? I did not want to hear this. Also I had heard so much about the Dead Sea in school. The Dead Sea is a unique place where the salt content is so high that you cannot sink. I had to experience this. On our last leg of journey from Wadi Rum to Madaba, we wanted to cover the Dead Sea.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yellowstone More to It Than Geysers</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/yellowstone-more-to-it-than-geysers.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2023 18:51:39 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/yellowstone-more-to-it-than-geysers.html</guid>
      <description>The friendly immigration officer was excited when I told him that I plan to visit Yellowstone National Park. He was from the same State, Wyoming. He said that if there was one place that one cannot really miss in the United States, it has got to be Yellowstone. I thanked him for his visa-stamping, generosity and his friendly advice. The drive from Salt Lake City to Jackson hole was through some of the most beautiful landscapes - vast areas of nothingness, beautiful rock formations and canyons in unbelievable shapes; everything in various shades of brown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Modest Trek Through a Grand Canyon</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/a-modest-trek-through-a-grand-canyon.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2023 18:43:05 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/a-modest-trek-through-a-grand-canyon.html</guid>
      <description>When someone I met recently was reciting the checklist of places he visited in the US and he mentioned New York, Vegas and Grand Canyon in one sentence, it disturbed me. He had achieved the feat of covering Grand Canyon within a day, from a helicopter, looking below. &amp;ldquo;Oh here&amp;rsquo;s the Grand Canyon. I&amp;rsquo;m done seeing it. Checked. Let&amp;rsquo;s move on&amp;rdquo;. I started thinking if that was possible at all for any place, let alone something as mammoth as the Grand Canyon, which has &amp;ldquo;grand&amp;rdquo; in its name itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Improbability of Castle Rock</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/the-improbability-of-castle-rock.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2023 08:43:33 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/the-improbability-of-castle-rock.html</guid>
      <description>Technically, Castlerock is only half a day away from some of the largest cities and innumerable towns of North Karnataka. For that matter, this little village (to use the official term for the place), is only a stone&amp;rsquo;s throw away from the touristy destinations such as Goa. But technicalities do not matter, because despite its long history, Castlerock seems to insist on folding itself away into a corner of the Western Ghats, mostly untouched by whatever is happening a few 100 kilometres around.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Walking the Maara With the Masai</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/walking-the-maara-with-maasai.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 06:50:06 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/walking-the-maara-with-maasai.html</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Could you repeat that?&amp;rdquo; I asked.
&amp;ldquo;Born during the rains from Sangok,&amp;rdquo; he said.
He was taller than me but not so tall as to undeniably fit the bill as a typical Masai; anywhere between 35 and 40 years of age. He wore a traditional Masai outfit that betrayed a bit of its costume nature thanks to being prim, proper and perhaps ironed out. A day before that, during the drive here I had seen a few Masai villagers who walked the road, with dust that refused to part with their faces and clothes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Amazon and its Tributaries</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/the-amazon-and-its-tributaries.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 05:06:19 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/the-amazon-and-its-tributaries.html</guid>
      <description>It was exactly how I had imagined it; perhaps better than that, because I remember sitting on that boat spellbound and self-aware that I had gone very quiet. The boat was navigating through the Maranon river in whose waters reflected the rising sun. The reflection moved ahead as we did ever so slowly, unhurried by the seeming speed that was implied by the engine itself which was the only thing I can remember as noise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homes on Stilts in the Amazon</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/homes-on-stilts-in-the-amazon.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 05:41:54 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/homes-on-stilts-in-the-amazon.html</guid>
      <description>The bare-bones dwelling on stilts appeared like creatures that could discreetly shy away inland when the river asserts its rights annually. I was excited like never before to step inside, as Jana (pronounced Yaana) explained the basics to us. Jana was a volunteer with the organization. She spoke with passion about the project; its mission and accomplishments. But mainly, she paused to speak about the mosquitoes when I inquired. I did not have an original inquiry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bryce : A Living Planetarium</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/bryce-a-living-planetarium.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2023 05:08:07 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/bryce-a-living-planetarium.html</guid>
      <description>It was not easy to comprehend the uniqueness of what was going on. There he was, a seemingly ordinary Park Ranger as he stood with his hands inside the pockets of his jacket to beat the chill of the night while he gave us a short lecture on what we were about to do and witness. I looked around. We were twenty of us who had signed up for the event, standing around in a circle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yellowstone where the Bisons still roam free</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/yellowstone-where-the-bisons-still-roam-free.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 22:13:30 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/yellowstone-where-the-bisons-still-roam-free.html</guid>
      <description>Vast stretches of grasslands till the horizon, spreading a greenish yellow carpet. The mountains far away decorate the edges of the grasslands. This land was owned by large herds of bison a long time ago till the western civilization set foot on the continent. The bison were bigger compared to their relatively smaller descendants we still see at Yellowstone today. The herds were larger too, of a scale that probably we might find it hard to imagine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bonding with Boda Boda driver over football</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/bonding-with-bodaboda-driver-over-football.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 21:59:40 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/bonding-with-bodaboda-driver-over-football.html</guid>
      <description>Leaving Bwindi Impenetrable rainforests was quite painful. Very soon we would be pushed from pristine rainforests to flatlands in no time, and it also meant dealing with more people. I took in my last sights and smells to the fullest - the starlit sky, the fresh cool mountain air and the huge dark shadows in the backdrop of the mountains that were not yet visible before day break. We had to leave at 6am, which meant most of the work, like packing up our tent, having a good cup of morning coffee and saying goodbyes to our hosts had to be done in the cold and in darkness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drive Through Ishasha</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/drive-through-ishasha.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 21:59:40 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/drive-through-ishasha.html</guid>
      <description>On the streets of the small town Kihiihi, we sat found an empty taxi and quickly boarded it. As we had the breakfast that we had packed from Bwindi, we saw that the shops were just starting to open. We saw them getting ready for the day by arranging their display pieces outside and cleaning the entrances. There were many people all dressed up and purposeful, walking in a single direction and very excited.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Camping by the Nile</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/camping-by-the-nile.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 21:57:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/camping-by-the-nile.html</guid>
      <description>After a nerve-wracking boda boda ride, we arrived at the gate of Nile River Explorers parched, exhausted and covered in mud. What I saw inside immediately lifted my mood; smiling faces, a bar overlooking the Nile and clean bathrooms. All I needed was a refreshing shower and a chilled beer. Both were readily available. Soon I found myself watching a group of macaques through my binoculars as I sipped beer at one of the river-front tables.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Howler Monkeys and the Ultimate Insult</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/howler-monkeys-and-the-ultimate-insult.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 09:24:27 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/howler-monkeys-and-the-ultimate-insult.html</guid>
      <description>We had walked for almost four hours now. With the dense canopy, it was hard to gauge the exact time of the day. I was starting to become a bit weary trying to keep one foot in front of the other, very gently and as noiselessly as possible. The mosquitoes took advantage of my tiredness and launched a fresh assault. My ears had to stay alert to grasp any sign of monkeys or birds around.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Incan Holy Grail</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/the-incan-holy-grail.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 09:20:32 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/the-incan-holy-grail.html</guid>
      <description>The early morning mist enhanced the view. I was surrounded by huge lush green mountains as our bus ascended, revealing various nooks and corners. The massive green mounds appeared to float in the mist, green rocks in a vast sea of white. The air was chilly outside our bus, getting colder with every bend of the ascent. I felt the excitement of having entered something sacred, something unspoilt and hidden. To reach this sacred site by walk might have been something more spiritual.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It is raining in Kerala!</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/rains-kerala.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 06:39:29 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/rains-kerala.html</guid>
      <description>The leaves are bright green of various shades, all washed and cleaned. Everything turns green - the plants, trees, walls, the floor, there is fresh growth all around. The trees and plants have all drank to their fill and stored up water for the next season. The soil has soaked up water and is saturated. Small streams of brown water are making their way through previously non-existent routes to lower lands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parque Arvi : Nature overlooking Medellin</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/parque-arvi-nature-overlooking-medellin.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 06:04:48 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/parque-arvi-nature-overlooking-medellin.html</guid>
      <description>Lucky are the people of Medellin that just an hour away from the busy city is one of the most beautiful parks that has not just breathtaking scenery but also some amazing biodiversity. When we ended up a whole day late in Medellin, at night, after our harrowing flight without our bags, little did I know that the misfortunes we faced the previous day would be compensated manifold by allowing us an extra day in the city that was not earlier planned.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tallest Palm in the World</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/tallest-palm-in-the-world.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 05:47:40 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/tallest-palm-in-the-world.html</guid>
      <description>I looked up a slender tree right in front of me, I lifted my head up and up, bent backwards as far as I could balance, but failed to see the crown. The morning sun was filtering through the scant crown of the giant palms blinding me as I squinted to gauge the full extent of its height. What seemed like a regular palm tree from a distance, unimpressive at a first glance, grew to unbelievable height as I approached it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Birdwatching in the Bolivian Amazon</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/amazing-birds-of-amazon.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 05:17:41 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/amazing-birds-of-amazon.html</guid>
      <description>If I had one favourite species, which bird would I really like to see? That was the question posed to me by Ricardo, our guide. My ambitious yet truthful answer to his question was, the Harpy&amp;rsquo;s Eagle. Ricardo smiled and I returned it. But we weren&amp;rsquo;t kidding each other. The bird watching experience here in the Amazon was supposed to be bit different, and by different, I mean very challenging when compared to what I had experienced up until then, back home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anchorage to Seward</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/anchorage-to-seward.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 05:03:21 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/anchorage-to-seward.html</guid>
      <description>There is something about trains that the moment someone mentions them, I get goosebumps; my heart starts racing and invariably. It is my wish to travel through some of the historical routes across the world, some spanning across continents and some meandering through unbelievable landscapes. I am always wondering about the ingenuity of the engineers who imagined a railroad and made it a reality. I try to incorporate train journeys to cover parts of my travel wherever feasible and affordable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Glacier Tour, Seward, Alaska</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/glacier-tour-seward.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2021 12:22:51 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/glacier-tour-seward.html</guid>
      <description>A bald eagle swooped in very close to our boat as we set off. The sun was struggling to shine through the dense grey clouds that threatened to pour down anytime. To be sailing off into the icy cold waters of the Pacific, with limited visibility, in the hope of seeing some glaciers, started to seem a bit ambitious. The misty cold morning confined most of us to the cozy interior of the boat, with little to look forward to other than this bald eagle and a friendly otter that did not seem to mind either our boat or the ice cold water.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Camping next to Savage river, Denali National Park</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/camping-at-savage-river.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 10:32:42 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/camping-at-savage-river.html</guid>
      <description>The weather was perfect when we entered Denali National Park. The sun was bright and our bus made a special stop on the way just for us to get a view of the majestic mountain Denali because it is not everyday that she presents herself in such glory. I have heard about the disappointment some people face when they spend two days at the National Park but fail to get a glimpse of the mountain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Denali at her raw best</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/denali-at-her-raw-best.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 10:17:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/denali-at-her-raw-best.html</guid>
      <description>Sitting in the park bus, I felt as though we were on a private tour of Denali National Park, just 4 of us, and our guide cum driver, Nick. It was to be the last trip for the day. That afternoon the entire Denali range was covered by thick clouds, it had started to get dark. Our chances of spotting wildlife also diminished with the daylight. With the rain looming in the horizon, we almost had the entire park for ourselves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An unforgettable encounter with our closest cousin</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/our-closest-cousin.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2019 19:17:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/our-closest-cousin.html</guid>
      <description>It was unmistakably the most beautiful place we would be staying in our entire trip. I could spend hours just looking at the mountains, and the rainforests and never cease to be amazed by their existence, being drawn into them further and further with every passing moment. I could be lost momentarily in mundane tasks like eating or washing clothes or fussing about the ants but the presence of the mountains constantly pulls me into a trance every now and then.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
