<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>photologue on Yﾄ》rﾄ［aya</title>
    <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/medium/photologue.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in photologue on Yﾄ》rﾄ［aya</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Jul 2021 20:23:18 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/medium/photologue/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bentota to Colombo by train, Sri Lanka</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/bentota-to-colombo-train-srilanka.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jul 2021 20:23:18 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/bentota-to-colombo-train-srilanka.html</guid>
      <description>Local train journey in Sri Lanka is a must do to see the culture up close. And, what&amp;rsquo;s better than the coastal rail route that offers some breathtaking views of the coast as well. Our started at this quaint little station called Bentota.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When the entire village came dressed in their finery</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/entire-village-finery.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2020 16:16:02 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/entire-village-finery.html</guid>
      <description>We decided to visit the Kibber Gompa on a day when we heard there was an important event. Not knowing what it was about, we went along, with our camera ready. We were surprised to find almost the entire village there, young and the old, with more joining in. There was an air of festivity and cheer. Not knowing the language, we smiled at whoever our eyes met with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wildlife Viewing in Denali National Park</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/wildlife-viewing-denali.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2020 16:16:02 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/wildlife-viewing-denali.html</guid>
      <description>We got onto the transit bus to Wonder Lake, one of the farthest campgrounds inside the Denali National park. Springtime being good tourist season, the bus was full and we managed to occupy the last second row. With my camera ready, I glued my eyes to the window of the bus, carefully scanning the vast landscape for any movement</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
