<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>photologue on Yﾄ》rﾄ［aya</title>
    <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/medium/photologue.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in photologue on Yﾄ》rﾄ［aya</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 17:02:59 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/medium/photologue/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Chiang Mai, Thailand</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/exploring-chiang-mai-thailand.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 17:02:59 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/exploring-chiang-mai-thailand.html</guid>
      <description>For most people, Thailand is Bangkok and vis-a-vis. That included us too, until we had the opportunity to travel to Chiang Mai which happens to be an equally (if not more) important city in Thailand and has much to offer. We hardly had enough time to explore enough but these photographs are from one of the days we felt adventurous enough to venture into the busy city streets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aboard the Madaraka Express from Mombasa to Nairobi, Kenya</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/mombasa-to-nairobi.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 17:00:59 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/mombasa-to-nairobi.html</guid>
      <description>East Africa is full of National Parks where some of the largest beasts to inhabit the earth, roam free. Sometimes, just sometimes, one gets to go through these national parks in a train. That is exactly what happened when we chose train as the mode of transport between Mombasa and Nairobi. The relatively new Standard Gauge Railway (SGR) that has been established between these two cities reaffirms the boundaries between Tsavo West and Tsavo East National Parks and is an experience that can be both unique and quite practical.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Descending the Himalayas in a Heritage Toy Train : Shimla to Kalka</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/descending-the-himalayas-heritage-toy-train.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 17:00:59 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/descending-the-himalayas-heritage-toy-train.html</guid>
      <description>The Shimla - Kalka Toy Train is hardly a realistic mode of transport today. A vestige of the colonial era, it only serves touristic value. But then again, we were tourists and we ought to behave like that. So we decided that it would be a worthy investment of our time to try out the journey in this colourful train that promises eye soothing views of the mountains and healthy mountain air for the lungs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From the Bolivian Highlands of La Paz, to Copacabana</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/bus-ride-to-copacabana.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 17:00:59 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/bus-ride-to-copacabana.html</guid>
      <description>There are many ways to travel from La Paz, Bolivia to Cusco, Peru. What we chose to do was use the services of Bolivia Hop which is a hop-on-hop-off bus service that also had an optional stopover at Copacabana. These pictures tell the story of the first leg of that journey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High Altitude Capital City, La Paz, Bolivia</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/high-altitude-capital-city-la-paz.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 17:00:59 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/high-altitude-capital-city-la-paz.html</guid>
      <description>La Paz, the highest capital city in the world. What does it feel like? We knew very little, because we mostly used La Paz as a hop-off point for our trip to other seductive corners of Bolivia, but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t a wonder that we could relegate to the back-burner for long. So off we went on a short walk around the city to find out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bentota to Colombo by train, Sri Lanka</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/bentota-to-colombo-train-srilanka.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jul 2021 20:23:18 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/bentota-to-colombo-train-srilanka.html</guid>
      <description>Local train journey in Sri Lanka is a must &amp;ldquo;to-do&amp;rdquo; to see the culture up close. And, what&amp;rsquo;s better than the coastal rail route that offers some breathtaking views of the coastline as well. Ours started at this quaint little station called Bentota.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When the entire village came dressed in their finery</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/entire-village-finery.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2020 16:16:02 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/entire-village-finery.html</guid>
      <description>We decided to visit the Kibber Gompa on a day when we heard there was an important event. Not knowing what it was about, we went along, with our camera ready. We were surprised to find almost the entire village there, young and the old, with more joining in. There was an air of festivity and cheer. Not knowing the language, we smiled at whoever our eyes met with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wildlife Viewing in Denali National Park</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/wildlife-viewing-denali.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2020 16:16:02 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/wildlife-viewing-denali.html</guid>
      <description>We got onto the transit bus to Wonder Lake, one of the farthest camp-grounds inside the Denali National park. Springtime being good tourist season, the bus was full and we managed to occupy the last second row. With my camera ready, I glued my eyes to the window of the bus, carefully scanning the vast landscape for any movement.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
