<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Beach on Yﾄ》rﾄ［aya</title>
    <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/types/beach.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Beach on Yﾄ》rﾄ［aya</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2023 07:54:34 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/types/beach/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Andaman Stargazing</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/andaman-stargazing.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2023 07:54:34 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/andaman-stargazing.html</guid>
      <description>I had this strange feeling of undeserved-ness when we sat there. My toes were digging into the sand into which a lot other tiny life forms were running into. The sea spoke with the same fervour, sometimes a little of it even caressing us as tiny droplets. It was just too good, just too real for it to be happening to us. The beach stretched miles to either side; usually we would be sharing it with a whole lot of humanity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dead Sea : World&#39;s Largest Outdoor Spa</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/dead-sea-worlds-largest-outdoor-spa.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2023 19:05:14 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/dead-sea-worlds-largest-outdoor-spa.html</guid>
      <description>You went to Jordan and you did not go to the Dead Sea? I did not want to hear this. Also I had heard so much about the Dead Sea in school. The Dead Sea is a unique place where the salt content is so high that you cannot sink. I had to experience this. On our last leg of journey from Wadi Rum to Madaba, we wanted to cover the Dead Sea.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Work Hard Beach Soft</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/work-hard-beach-soft.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 06:54:19 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/work-hard-beach-soft.html</guid>
      <description>As we drove farther to the west, the landscape changed from the usual staple of large buildings with their even-larger parking lots, to one, that in appearance, had a little more of what I conjure up in my mind whenever I come across the word &amp;lsquo;California&amp;rsquo;. A friend of mine had once told me I&amp;rsquo;d fit right in because I was a tree-hugger. In the literal sense of that term, at least, this seemed the most likely possibility as I witnessed here some of the largest, tallest and oldest redwood trees; trees whose circumference would have made me look like an insect hanging on to the bark when attempting to hug one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Night at Southbeach Miami</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/a-night-at-southbeach-miami.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 22:09:04 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/a-night-at-southbeach-miami.html</guid>
      <description>It was our attempt to soak in as much Miami as we could in the short time we spent at South Beach. Night life at South Beach was exactly how I had visualized from my exposure to American films. It was all a grand party, a party that was on every night, without a break. So, we got ready to join this party, first as observers, from the periphery, then making our entry into this fantasy world of neon lights, loud Latino music, dance parties, speeding auto-mobiles and unlimited cocktails.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day trip to Playa Blanca, Colombia</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/day-trip-to-playa-blanca-colombia.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 05:57:05 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/day-trip-to-playa-blanca-colombia.html</guid>
      <description>The thought of white sandy beaches with blue waters felt almost too good to be true. Tourists mostly head to Cartagena to experience exactly this. The Caribbean islands are famous for some of the most pristine and picturesque beaches in the world. We were surprisingly one of the few who were in Cartagena without a clear intention of soaking in the sun on one of these beaches. Reluctantly, one morning, we walked to one of the hostels which was arranging day tours to Playa Blanca, which, in Spanish, simply means the White Beach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>By the Caribbean coast of Cartagena</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/by-the-caribbean-coast-of-cartagena.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 05:54:07 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/by-the-caribbean-coast-of-cartagena.html</guid>
      <description>If you would find yourself stuck in a time loop, where you find yourself waking up in the same place each day for the rest of your life, where would you like it to be? When I ask myself this question, one of the places that came to my mind was Cartagena. This coastal city of Northern Colombia is one of those places that offers many experiences at the same time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Words cannot describe vibes, Arambol, Goa</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/return-to-arambol-goa.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 16:57:03 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/return-to-arambol-goa.html</guid>
      <description>On our very first trip to Goa, the mystical beach of Arambol was but a short two hour visit; an interlude between the many places we visited. Back then, it was sort of an insatiable hunger, perhaps greed even to &amp;ldquo;see it all&amp;rdquo;. It was a ride on a ramshackle rented bike from Vagator - where we were shacked up; an evening ride got us there just in time for a spectacular sunset at the Arambol beach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A walk through Stone Town, Zanzibar</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/stonetown-zanzibar.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 19:02:15 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/stonetown-zanzibar.html</guid>
      <description>Just outside, you find yourself in a typical African town, with people getting about their routine work. There is traffic, pollution, vehicles honking, hawkers selling everything from bread, fruits, vegetables, newspaper to bags, shoes, clothes and people haggling for a good bargain; burqa clad school girls gossiping in small groups, giggling, waiting for their bus; high school boys trying to look like grown up men, wearing their traditional cap and gown, but their their school bags giving them away.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Andaman Forest Walk</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/andaman-forest-walk.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 12:31:29 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/andaman-forest-walk.html</guid>
      <description>Neil Island, being one of the smaller ones of the Andaman archipelago, is an inconspicuous dot in the vast blue waters of the mighty Indian Ocean. Here one gets the sensation of being &amp;lsquo;bound&amp;rsquo; or &amp;rsquo;limited&amp;rsquo; by the land area. Getting to experience both sunrise and sunset on the same day was something that I looked forward to on small islands and Neil had not disappointed me in that respect. In just a couple of days of arriving on Neil Island, I got the feeling that we had already explored everything there was worth exploring.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
