<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>City on Yﾄ》rﾄ［aya</title>
    <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/types/city.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in City on Yﾄ》rﾄ［aya</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 05:15:17 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/types/city/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Getting Stuck at Tumbes</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/getting-stuck-at-tumbes.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 05:15:17 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/getting-stuck-at-tumbes.html</guid>
      <description>If getting to Tumbes wasn&amp;rsquo;t easy, getting out wasn&amp;rsquo;t any easier either. As I sat staring at the news-reporter on the TV and reading the news-ticker which was in English reporting on the riots in Ecuador, I felt completely helpless and hopeless. All the local TV channels were reporting on the same topic and no amount of switching channels was going to change anything for us. We were simply destined to be stuck in that mostly unknown border town till something changed radically in the next few days or we retreated in defeat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Whirling Dervishes of Turkey</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/the-whirling-dervishes-of-turkey.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 21:52:04 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/the-whirling-dervishes-of-turkey.html</guid>
      <description>Istanbul&amp;rsquo;s reputation as a historical city with great culture and tradition was one of the reasons we decided to generously let it occupy a greater part of our Turkey trip. While reading about the culture, I came upon its Sufi tradition, known as the Mevlevi Order; inspired by &amp;ldquo;Mevlana&amp;rdquo; Rumi, the famous Islamic mystical poet and spiritual master. Sufism is a form of Islam which emphasizes the inward search for God through direct connect and promotes realization of God through love and music.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Nairobi to Narok</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/from-nairobi-to-narok.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 06:25:47 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/from-nairobi-to-narok.html</guid>
      <description>The notorious reputation of Matatus that I had gathered from various forums preceded their appearance. This made me look at each of them with horror, like they were assassins. When I saw them while crossing the street, I would jump and step back, holding my partner&amp;rsquo;s hand tightly, with my eyes shut, as though, they were on a mission to kill; as if they would, at any time, veer off the road, into the footpath and run me over.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>By the Caribbean coast of Cartagena</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/by-the-caribbean-coast-of-cartagena.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 05:54:07 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/by-the-caribbean-coast-of-cartagena.html</guid>
      <description>If you would find yourself stuck in a time loop, where you find yourself waking up in the same place each day for the rest of your life, where would you like it to be? When I ask myself this question, one of the places that came to my mind was Cartagena. This coastal city of Northern Colombia is one of those places that offers many experiences at the same time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No one can stop looking at Jardin</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/no-one-can-stop-looking-at-jardin.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 05:42:29 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/no-one-can-stop-looking-at-jardin.html</guid>
      <description>I have many a times sifted through my memories to focus on the colourful postcards in my mind&amp;rsquo;s eye that for me represent Jardin, and I have wondered, what was it that I did there for a couple of days? As simple as it might sound, nothing really. Absolutely nothing if I were to be accurate. Yes. If there is a really good venue for doing nothing, then it had to be Jardin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trip to a Bolivian Consulate</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/trip-to-a-bolivian-consulate.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 05:30:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/trip-to-a-bolivian-consulate.html</guid>
      <description>Most of the tourists who land at the Calama Airport in Northern Chile have but one purpose which is to book a direct taxi to their real destination, San Pedro de Atacama, the jewel of the Atacama desert, a picturesque town that is tailored around tourism. Calama, on the other hand is a mining town visited by workers - both short and long term - and people who have some business connected to mining.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Live Music Bar at Goreme, Cappadocia, Turkey</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/live-music-bar-goreme.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 16:57:03 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/live-music-bar-goreme.html</guid>
      <description>The cold air was broken by the white trail of warm breath as I walked into the night. The bar was just a block away from where we stayed. The tables were only beginning to be occupied. We asked for a table for two, ordered some Raki that came with some soft bread and dips. The lights were dim and created a warm and cozy atmosphere. Everyone were dressed in party-wear, colourful, resplendent with makeup and jewellery.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
