<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Turkey on Yﾄ》rﾄ［aya</title>
    <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/countries/turkey.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Turkey on Yﾄ》rﾄ［aya</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 21:52:04 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/countries/turkey/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Whirling Dervishes of Turkey</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/the-whirling-dervishes-of-turkey.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 21:52:04 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/the-whirling-dervishes-of-turkey.html</guid>
      <description>Istanbul&amp;rsquo;s reputation as a historical city with great culture and tradition was one of the reasons we decided to generously let it occupy a greater part of our Turkey trip. While reading about the culture, I came upon its Sufi tradition, known as the Mevlevi Order; inspired by &amp;ldquo;Mevlana&amp;rdquo; Rumi, the famous Islamic mystical poet and spiritual master. Sufism is a form of Islam which emphasizes the inward search for God through direct connect and promotes realization of God through love and music.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Turkish Bath at a Hamam, Istanbul</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/hamam-at-istanbul-turkey.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 19:55:03 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/hamam-at-istanbul-turkey.html</guid>
      <description>After having spent two months backpacking and camping, the idea of a nice hot Turkish bath seemed most desirable. Although I did not have a first hand experience about a Hamam, having read a few blogs about it, I felt I was bold enough to give it a try. Having been to Istanbul and not trying the Hamam was not acceptable for me. I kept putting it off for the first couple of days, with certain inhibitions getting the better of my cravings for a hot bath.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Staying in a cavehouse at Goreme, Cappadocia</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/goreme-cappadocia-homestay.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 19:32:07 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/goreme-cappadocia-homestay.html</guid>
      <description>Goreme was a beautiful town in a valley beyond the vast, brown mountains and large smooth rocks that resembled endless mounds of mud. That morning, we were transferred to a mini-bus after an overnight journey in a comfortable, large bus. We had got used to the efficiency of this country, and the general goodness of people, so we only had to step out of the bus and step into the smaller bus, without having to fuss about our luggages, which were perfectly tagged and transferred promptly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azaan at Sultanahmet, Istanbul</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/azaan-at-sultanahmet-istanbul.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 18:58:38 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/azaan-at-sultanahmet-istanbul.html</guid>
      <description>Walking the crowded streets of Sultanahmet late evening, I was trying to negotiate a road crossing, just as a tram passed the street. The wind was chill yet filled with the aroma of the food from the roadside restaurants. Just then, I heard the most melodious tune somewhere far that made me freeze. I just stood there mesmerized, holding on to every single sound that came out from this singer. The words &amp;ldquo;Allahu Akhbar&amp;rdquo;, probably heard several times in my lifetime, had never before sounded so beautiful, so profound.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Live Music Bar at Goreme, Cappadocia, Turkey</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/live-music-bar-goreme.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 16:57:03 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/live-music-bar-goreme.html</guid>
      <description>The cold air was broken by the white trail of warm breath as I walked into the night. The bar was just a block away from where we stayed. The tables were only beginning to be occupied. We asked for a table for two, ordered some Raki that came with some soft bread and dips. The lights were dim and created a warm and cozy atmosphere. Everyone were dressed in party-wear, colourful, resplendent with makeup and jewellery.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
