<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Historical on Yﾄ》rﾄ［aya</title>
    <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/types/historical.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Historical on Yﾄ》rﾄ［aya</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 05:15:17 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/types/historical/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Getting Stuck at Tumbes</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/getting-stuck-at-tumbes.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 05:15:17 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/getting-stuck-at-tumbes.html</guid>
      <description>If getting to Tumbes wasn&amp;rsquo;t easy, getting out wasn&amp;rsquo;t any easier either. As I sat staring at the news-reporter on the TV and reading the news-ticker which was in English reporting on the riots in Ecuador, I felt completely helpless and hopeless. All the local TV channels were reporting on the same topic and no amount of switching channels was going to change anything for us. We were simply destined to be stuck in that mostly unknown border town till something changed radically in the next few days or we retreated in defeat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Short Trek to a Lake in the Sky</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/a-short-trek-to-a-lake-in-the-sky.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 06:08:21 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/a-short-trek-to-a-lake-in-the-sky.html</guid>
      <description>Our host, over evening cup of hot tea mentioned about the Dhankar lake that was a must visit. I was happy that there were not many guests either at our homestay or any other around, which meant that there would be lesser crowds at the lake the next morning. Our host offered to pack us Aloo Paranthas to carry on our little expedition. We started off on a trail from Dhankar Gompa that would take us further higher by another 200-300 metres, to this high altitude lake at 4150 meters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Incan Holy Grail</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/the-incan-holy-grail.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 09:20:32 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/the-incan-holy-grail.html</guid>
      <description>The early morning mist enhanced the view. I was surrounded by huge lush green mountains as our bus ascended, revealing various nooks and corners. The massive green mounds appeared to float in the mist, green rocks in a vast sea of white. The air was chilly outside our bus, getting colder with every bend of the ascent. I felt the excitement of having entered something sacred, something unspoilt and hidden. To reach this sacred site by walk might have been something more spiritual.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>By the Caribbean coast of Cartagena</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/by-the-caribbean-coast-of-cartagena.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 05:54:07 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/by-the-caribbean-coast-of-cartagena.html</guid>
      <description>If you would find yourself stuck in a time loop, where you find yourself waking up in the same place each day for the rest of your life, where would you like it to be? When I ask myself this question, one of the places that came to my mind was Cartagena. This coastal city of Northern Colombia is one of those places that offers many experiences at the same time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No one can stop looking at Jardin</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/no-one-can-stop-looking-at-jardin.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 05:42:29 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/no-one-can-stop-looking-at-jardin.html</guid>
      <description>I have many a times sifted through my memories to focus on the colourful postcards in my mind&amp;rsquo;s eye that for me represent Jardin, and I have wondered, what was it that I did there for a couple of days? As simple as it might sound, nothing really. Absolutely nothing if I were to be accurate. Yes. If there is a really good venue for doing nothing, then it had to be Jardin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talkeetna : Alaskan Hinterland</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/talkeetna-alaskan-hinterland.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 03:25:04 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/talkeetna-alaskan-hinterland.html</guid>
      <description>As I walked the barely asphalted road that led us from the well wooded section that closely guarded our hideout into what was the active and colourful part of the town, I started realizing why I liked this place so much. For one, it was unlike the rest of the United States. There was an authentic small-town feel to it. Not the sterile and templated small-town that one gets used to in the U.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Walking the Wadi Rum, Jordan</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/walking-the-wadi-rum-jordan.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 20:28:29 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/walking-the-wadi-rum-jordan.html</guid>
      <description>How far would one have to drive out to actually get somewhere? Strange were my thoughts as I stared out of the SUV into the emptiness all around. Did we really have to get anywhere at all? In a desert like Wadi Rum it took only an hour worth of driving to get to a point where one&amp;rsquo;s source and destination started to look the same and considering we did not have any specific goal it was only logical to rely on our host who was intently driving onwards on a trail that could not have been older than a week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Turkish Bath at a Hamam, Istanbul</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/hamam-at-istanbul-turkey.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 19:55:03 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/hamam-at-istanbul-turkey.html</guid>
      <description>After having spent two months backpacking and camping, the idea of a nice hot Turkish bath seemed most desirable. Although I did not have a first hand experience about a Hamam, having read a few blogs about it, I felt I was bold enough to give it a try. Having been to Istanbul and not trying the Hamam was not acceptable for me. I kept putting it off for the first couple of days, with certain inhibitions getting the better of my cravings for a hot bath.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Staying in a cavehouse at Goreme, Cappadocia</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/goreme-cappadocia-homestay.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 19:32:07 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/goreme-cappadocia-homestay.html</guid>
      <description>Goreme was a beautiful town in a valley beyond the vast, brown mountains and large smooth rocks that resembled endless mounds of mud. That morning, we were transferred to a mini-bus after an overnight journey in a comfortable, large bus. We had got used to the efficiency of this country, and the general goodness of people, so we only had to step out of the bus and step into the smaller bus, without having to fuss about our luggages, which were perfectly tagged and transferred promptly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azaan at Sultanahmet, Istanbul</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/azaan-at-sultanahmet-istanbul.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 18:58:38 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/azaan-at-sultanahmet-istanbul.html</guid>
      <description>Walking the crowded streets of Sultanahmet late evening, I was trying to negotiate a road crossing, just as a tram passed the street. The wind was chill yet filled with the aroma of the food from the roadside restaurants. Just then, I heard the most melodious tune somewhere far that made me freeze. I just stood there mesmerized, holding on to every single sound that came out from this singer. The words &amp;ldquo;Allahu Akhbar&amp;rdquo;, probably heard several times in my lifetime, had never before sounded so beautiful, so profound.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A walk through Stone Town, Zanzibar</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/stonetown-zanzibar.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 19:02:15 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/stonetown-zanzibar.html</guid>
      <description>Just outside, you find yourself in a typical African town, with people getting about their routine work. There is traffic, pollution, vehicles honking, hawkers selling everything from bread, fruits, vegetables, newspaper to bags, shoes, clothes and people haggling for a good bargain; burqa clad school girls gossiping in small groups, giggling, waiting for their bus; high school boys trying to look like grown up men, wearing their traditional cap and gown, but their their school bags giving them away.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
