<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2017 on Yﾄ》rﾄ［aya</title>
    <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/year/2017.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2017 on Yﾄ》rﾄ［aya</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 17:00:59 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/year/2017/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Descending the Himalayas in a Heritage Toy Train : Shimla to Kalka</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/descending-the-himalayas-heritage-toy-train.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 17:00:59 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/descending-the-himalayas-heritage-toy-train.html</guid>
      <description>The Shimla - Kalka Toy Train is hardly a realistic mode of transport today. A vestige of the colonial era, it only serves touristic value. But then again, we were tourists and we ought to behave like that. So we decided that it would be a worthy investment of our time to try out the journey in this colourful train that promises eye soothing views of the mountains and healthy mountain air for the lungs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Short Trek to a Lake in the Sky</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/a-short-trek-to-a-lake-in-the-sky.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 06:08:21 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/a-short-trek-to-a-lake-in-the-sky.html</guid>
      <description>Our host, over evening cup of hot tea mentioned about the Dhankar lake that was a must visit. I was happy that there were not many guests either at our homestay or any other around, which meant that there would be lesser crowds at the lake the next morning. Our host offered to pack us Aloo Paranthas to carry on our little expedition. We started off on a trail from Dhankar Gompa that would take us further higher by another 200-300 metres, to this high altitude lake at 4150 meters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life in Spiti</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/life-in-spiti.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 21:22:41 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/life-in-spiti.html</guid>
      <description>I sat there as though in a trance; watching how the horizontal yarn moved through the hundreds of threads that were hanging along the frame of the loom. Her hands moving rhythmically in a quick, yet, skilful way made me wonder how it might feel to sit there in solitude, patiently working on the pattern. It was meditative. I had a hundred questions to ask her. I hesitated. Would she get disturbed by my interruption and make a mistake?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When the entire village came dressed in their finery</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/entire-village-finery.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2020 16:16:02 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/entire-village-finery.html</guid>
      <description>We decided to visit the Kibber Gompa on a day when we heard there was an important event. Not knowing what it was about, we went along, with our camera ready. We were surprised to find almost the entire village there, young and the old, with more joining in. There was an air of festivity and cheer. Not knowing the language, we smiled at whoever our eyes met with.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
