<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>October on Yﾄ》rﾄ［aya</title>
    <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/month/october.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in October on Yﾄ》rﾄ［aya</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 17:00:59 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/month/october/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Descending the Himalayas in a Heritage Toy Train : Shimla to Kalka</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/descending-the-himalayas-heritage-toy-train.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 17:00:59 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/descending-the-himalayas-heritage-toy-train.html</guid>
      <description>The Shimla - Kalka Toy Train is hardly a realistic mode of transport today. A vestige of the colonial era, it only serves touristic value. But then again, we were tourists and we ought to behave like that. So we decided that it would be a worthy investment of our time to try out the journey in this colourful train that promises eye soothing views of the mountains and healthy mountain air for the lungs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yellowstone More to It Than Geysers</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/yellowstone-more-to-it-than-geysers.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2023 18:51:39 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/yellowstone-more-to-it-than-geysers.html</guid>
      <description>The friendly immigration officer was excited when I told him that I plan to visit Yellowstone National Park. He was from the same State, Wyoming. He said that if there was one place that one cannot really miss in the United States, it has got to be Yellowstone. I thanked him for his visa-stamping, generosity and his friendly advice. The drive from Salt Lake City to Jackson hole was through some of the most beautiful landscapes - vast areas of nothingness, beautiful rock formations and canyons in unbelievable shapes; everything in various shades of brown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Modest Trek Through a Grand Canyon</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/a-modest-trek-through-a-grand-canyon.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2023 18:43:05 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/a-modest-trek-through-a-grand-canyon.html</guid>
      <description>When someone I met recently was reciting the checklist of places he visited in the US and he mentioned New York, Vegas and Grand Canyon in one sentence, it disturbed me. He had achieved the feat of covering Grand Canyon within a day, from a helicopter, looking below. &amp;ldquo;Oh here&amp;rsquo;s the Grand Canyon. I&amp;rsquo;m done seeing it. Checked. Let&amp;rsquo;s move on&amp;rdquo;. I started thinking if that was possible at all for any place, let alone something as mammoth as the Grand Canyon, which has &amp;ldquo;grand&amp;rdquo; in its name itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Short Trek to a Lake in the Sky</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/a-short-trek-to-a-lake-in-the-sky.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 06:08:21 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/a-short-trek-to-a-lake-in-the-sky.html</guid>
      <description>Our host, over evening cup of hot tea mentioned about the Dhankar lake that was a must visit. I was happy that there were not many guests either at our homestay or any other around, which meant that there would be lesser crowds at the lake the next morning. Our host offered to pack us Aloo Paranthas to carry on our little expedition. We started off on a trail from Dhankar Gompa that would take us further higher by another 200-300 metres, to this high altitude lake at 4150 meters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bryce : A Living Planetarium</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/bryce-a-living-planetarium.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2023 05:08:07 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/bryce-a-living-planetarium.html</guid>
      <description>It was not easy to comprehend the uniqueness of what was going on. There he was, a seemingly ordinary Park Ranger as he stood with his hands inside the pockets of his jacket to beat the chill of the night while he gave us a short lecture on what we were about to do and witness. I looked around. We were twenty of us who had signed up for the event, standing around in a circle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yellowstone where the Bisons still roam free</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/yellowstone-where-the-bisons-still-roam-free.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 22:13:30 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/yellowstone-where-the-bisons-still-roam-free.html</guid>
      <description>Vast stretches of grasslands till the horizon, spreading a greenish yellow carpet. The mountains far away decorate the edges of the grasslands. This land was owned by large herds of bison a long time ago till the western civilization set foot on the continent. The bison were bigger compared to their relatively smaller descendants we still see at Yellowstone today. The herds were larger too, of a scale that probably we might find it hard to imagine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Night at Southbeach Miami</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/a-night-at-southbeach-miami.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 22:09:04 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/a-night-at-southbeach-miami.html</guid>
      <description>It was our attempt to soak in as much Miami as we could in the short time we spent at South Beach. Night life at South Beach was exactly how I had visualized from my exposure to American films. It was all a grand party, a party that was on every night, without a break. So, we got ready to join this party, first as observers, from the periphery, then making our entry into this fantasy world of neon lights, loud Latino music, dance parties, speeding auto-mobiles and unlimited cocktails.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life in Spiti</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/life-in-spiti.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 21:22:41 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/life-in-spiti.html</guid>
      <description>I sat there as though in a trance; watching how the horizontal yarn moved through the hundreds of threads that were hanging along the frame of the loom. Her hands moving rhythmically in a quick, yet, skilful way made me wonder how it might feel to sit there in solitude, patiently working on the pattern. It was meditative. I had a hundred questions to ask her. I hesitated. Would she get disturbed by my interruption and make a mistake?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When the entire village came dressed in their finery</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/entire-village-finery.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2020 16:16:02 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/entire-village-finery.html</guid>
      <description>We decided to visit the Kibber Gompa on a day when we heard there was an important event. Not knowing what it was about, we went along, with our camera ready. We were surprised to find almost the entire village there, young and the old, with more joining in. There was an air of festivity and cheer. Not knowing the language, we smiled at whoever our eyes met with.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
