<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Trekking on Yﾄ》rﾄ［aya</title>
    <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/types/trekking.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Trekking on Yﾄ》rﾄ［aya</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2023 18:43:05 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/types/trekking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Modest Trek Through a Grand Canyon</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/a-modest-trek-through-a-grand-canyon.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2023 18:43:05 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/a-modest-trek-through-a-grand-canyon.html</guid>
      <description>When someone I met recently was reciting the checklist of places he visited in the US and he mentioned New York, Vegas and Grand Canyon in one sentence, it disturbed me. He had achieved the feat of covering Grand Canyon within a day, from a helicopter, looking below. &amp;ldquo;Oh here&amp;rsquo;s the Grand Canyon. I&amp;rsquo;m done seeing it. Checked. Let&amp;rsquo;s move on&amp;rdquo;. I started thinking if that was possible at all for any place, let alone something as mammoth as the Grand Canyon, which has &amp;ldquo;grand&amp;rdquo; in its name itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Walking the Maara With the Masai</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/walking-the-maara-with-maasai.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 06:50:06 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/walking-the-maara-with-maasai.html</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Could you repeat that?&amp;rdquo; I asked.
&amp;ldquo;Born during the rains from Sangok,&amp;rdquo; he said.
He was taller than me but not so tall as to undeniably fit the bill as a typical Masai; anywhere between 35 and 40 years of age. He wore a traditional Masai outfit that betrayed a bit of its costume nature thanks to being prim, proper and perhaps ironed out. A day before that, during the drive here I had seen a few Masai villagers who walked the road, with dust that refused to part with their faces and clothes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tallest Palm in the World</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/tallest-palm-in-the-world.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 05:47:40 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/tallest-palm-in-the-world.html</guid>
      <description>I looked up a slender tree right in front of me, I lifted my head up and up, bent backwards as far as I could balance, but failed to see the crown. The morning sun was filtering through the scant crown of the giant palms blinding me as I squinted to gauge the full extent of its height. What seemed like a regular palm tree from a distance, unimpressive at a first glance, grew to unbelievable height as I approached it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We still have not seen the Tapir</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/we-still-have-not-seen-the-tapir.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 05:11:21 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/we-still-have-not-seen-the-tapir.html</guid>
      <description>At 4am, I could see the faint light in the other tents. Braving the cold and in complete darkness with the help of a flash-light, I managed to crawl out of mine. The moonless sky shone with a million stars. Wearing our rubber boots our team of four started walking towards the forest. The cicadas seemed to cheer us on and follow us into the darkness as we moved in. The eerie ambience was complemented by a million other insects that were probably protesting as we walked through the maze of branches and roots.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A walk through Sinharaja Forest Reserve, Sri Lanka</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/sinharaja-forest-reserve-srilanka.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 19:33:32 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/sinharaja-forest-reserve-srilanka.html</guid>
      <description>I had imagined this tear-drop-shaped island country always to have been green; a green dot floating in the endless blue waters of the mighty Indian Ocean. I would like to believe that it was once covered with dense impenetrable tropical rainforests, with innumerable waterfalls and countless streams. It was perhaps my effort to recreate this lost experience, when I chose trekking through the Sinharaja Forest Reserve as one of my first experiences in Sri Lanka.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Trek to Kuari Pass and Pangarchulla, Uttarakhand</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/trek-to-kuari-pass-pangarchulla.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2019 19:32:50 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/trek-to-kuari-pass-pangarchulla.html</guid>
      <description>My back was unaccustomed to the heavy load. It was more than a year since I had been on any serious multi-day hike. And, even though we had hired a couple of porters and a guide to carry the camping equipment and the cooking essentials, even the personal items that I had signed up to haul was seeming heavier than I had imagined. The moment I got out of the jeep and started walking through the narrow lanes of the village Dhak, two thoughts were on my mind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An unforgettable encounter with our closest cousin</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/our-closest-cousin.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2019 19:17:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/our-closest-cousin.html</guid>
      <description>It was unmistakably the most beautiful place we would be staying in our entire trip. I could spend hours just looking at the mountains, and the rainforests and never cease to be amazed by their existence, being drawn into them further and further with every passing moment. I could be lost momentarily in mundane tasks like eating or washing clothes or fussing about the ants but the presence of the mountains constantly pulls me into a trance every now and then.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
