<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tanzania on Yﾄ》rﾄ［aya</title>
    <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/countries/tanzania.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tanzania on Yﾄ》rﾄ［aya</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 21:36:01 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/countries/tanzania/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Volunteering for Food</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/volunteering-for-food.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 21:36:01 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/volunteering-for-food.html</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Why we chose Bunda, or should I say, why Bunda chose us?&amp;rdquo; our host Aysha spoke of her reason for choosing to make this sleepy village her home. I sat in front of her nervously, hoping that the voice was clearly recording and we would complete the interview in a single take. She was dressed up for the interview, had rehearsed the questions, but we chose to keep the interview itself spontaneous, impromptu and she was eager to get it right.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Land Border Crossing from Kenya to Tanzania</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/land-border-crossing-from-kenya-to-tanzania.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 21:31:49 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/land-border-crossing-from-kenya-to-tanzania.html</guid>
      <description>We left Kisii early in the morning, after a breakfast consisting of coffee and Mandazi. The Matatu stand was close to where we stayed and this gave us the advantage of walking right up to it with our backpacks. As expected, someone &amp;ldquo;fished&amp;rdquo; us and led us through the maze of Matatus parked to a specific one that said Kisii Direct. We had learned that &amp;ldquo;direct&amp;rdquo; means no changes/transfers midway. Then again, we knew enough by now - practical and experienced in this part of the world - that what they promised was not always what they delivered.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A walk through Stone Town, Zanzibar</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/stonetown-zanzibar.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 19:02:15 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/stonetown-zanzibar.html</guid>
      <description>Just outside, you find yourself in a typical African town, with people getting about their routine work. There is traffic, pollution, vehicles honking, hawkers selling everything from bread, fruits, vegetables, newspaper to bags, shoes, clothes and people haggling for a good bargain; burqa clad school girls gossiping in small groups, giggling, waiting for their bus; high school boys trying to look like grown up men, wearing their traditional cap and gown, but their their school bags giving them away.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
