<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Colombia on Yﾄ》rﾄ［aya</title>
    <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/countries/colombia.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Colombia on Yﾄ》rﾄ［aya</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 06:04:48 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/countries/colombia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Parque Arvi : Nature overlooking Medellin</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/parque-arvi-nature-overlooking-medellin.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 06:04:48 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/parque-arvi-nature-overlooking-medellin.html</guid>
      <description>Lucky are the people of Medellin that just an hour away from the busy city is one of the most beautiful parks that has not just breathtaking scenery but also some amazing biodiversity. When we ended up a whole day late in Medellin, at night, after our harrowing flight without our bags, little did I know that the misfortunes we faced the previous day would be compensated manifold by allowing us an extra day in the city that was not earlier planned.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day trip to Playa Blanca, Colombia</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/day-trip-to-playa-blanca-colombia.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 05:57:05 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/day-trip-to-playa-blanca-colombia.html</guid>
      <description>The thought of white sandy beaches with blue waters felt almost too good to be true. Tourists mostly head to Cartagena to experience exactly this. The Caribbean islands are famous for some of the most pristine and picturesque beaches in the world. We were surprisingly one of the few who were in Cartagena without a clear intention of soaking in the sun on one of these beaches. Reluctantly, one morning, we walked to one of the hostels which was arranging day tours to Playa Blanca, which, in Spanish, simply means the White Beach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>By the Caribbean coast of Cartagena</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/by-the-caribbean-coast-of-cartagena.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 05:54:07 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/by-the-caribbean-coast-of-cartagena.html</guid>
      <description>If you would find yourself stuck in a time loop, where you find yourself waking up in the same place each day for the rest of your life, where would you like it to be? When I ask myself this question, one of the places that came to my mind was Cartagena. This coastal city of Northern Colombia is one of those places that offers many experiences at the same time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tallest Palm in the World</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/tallest-palm-in-the-world.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 05:47:40 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/tallest-palm-in-the-world.html</guid>
      <description>I looked up a slender tree right in front of me, I lifted my head up and up, bent backwards as far as I could balance, but failed to see the crown. The morning sun was filtering through the scant crown of the giant palms blinding me as I squinted to gauge the full extent of its height. What seemed like a regular palm tree from a distance, unimpressive at a first glance, grew to unbelievable height as I approached it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No one can stop looking at Jardin</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/no-one-can-stop-looking-at-jardin.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 05:42:29 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/no-one-can-stop-looking-at-jardin.html</guid>
      <description>I have many a times sifted through my memories to focus on the colourful postcards in my mind&amp;rsquo;s eye that for me represent Jardin, and I have wondered, what was it that I did there for a couple of days? As simple as it might sound, nothing really. Absolutely nothing if I were to be accurate. Yes. If there is a really good venue for doing nothing, then it had to be Jardin.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
