<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2018 on Yﾄ》rﾄ［aya</title>
    <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/year/2018.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2018 on Yﾄ》rﾄ［aya</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2023 19:05:14 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/year/2018/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dead Sea : World&#39;s Largest Outdoor Spa</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/dead-sea-worlds-largest-outdoor-spa.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2023 19:05:14 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/dead-sea-worlds-largest-outdoor-spa.html</guid>
      <description>You went to Jordan and you did not go to the Dead Sea? I did not want to hear this. Also I had heard so much about the Dead Sea in school. The Dead Sea is a unique place where the salt content is so high that you cannot sink. I had to experience this. On our last leg of journey from Wadi Rum to Madaba, we wanted to cover the Dead Sea.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yellowstone More to It Than Geysers</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/yellowstone-more-to-it-than-geysers.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2023 18:51:39 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/yellowstone-more-to-it-than-geysers.html</guid>
      <description>The friendly immigration officer was excited when I told him that I plan to visit Yellowstone National Park. He was from the same State, Wyoming. He said that if there was one place that one cannot really miss in the United States, it has got to be Yellowstone. I thanked him for his visa-stamping, generosity and his friendly advice. The drive from Salt Lake City to Jackson hole was through some of the most beautiful landscapes - vast areas of nothingness, beautiful rock formations and canyons in unbelievable shapes; everything in various shades of brown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Modest Trek Through a Grand Canyon</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/a-modest-trek-through-a-grand-canyon.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2023 18:43:05 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/a-modest-trek-through-a-grand-canyon.html</guid>
      <description>When someone I met recently was reciting the checklist of places he visited in the US and he mentioned New York, Vegas and Grand Canyon in one sentence, it disturbed me. He had achieved the feat of covering Grand Canyon within a day, from a helicopter, looking below. &amp;ldquo;Oh here&amp;rsquo;s the Grand Canyon. I&amp;rsquo;m done seeing it. Checked. Let&amp;rsquo;s move on&amp;rdquo;. I started thinking if that was possible at all for any place, let alone something as mammoth as the Grand Canyon, which has &amp;ldquo;grand&amp;rdquo; in its name itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Land Border Crossing From Kenya to Uganda</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/land-border-crossing-from-kenya-to-uganda.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 06:07:37 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/land-border-crossing-from-kenya-to-uganda.html</guid>
      <description>They say, there is always a first time for everything. I remember some of my firsts and not all of them are pleasant ones. As the bus pulled up into a nondescript corner of the street and the conductor announced that we had arrived, I felt another first; anxious thoughts about the next few minutes. The last few hours were spent in the knowledge of what we were up to but anxiety had not taken over due to the novelty of what was on offer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Walking the Maara With the Masai</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/walking-the-maara-with-maasai.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 06:50:06 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/walking-the-maara-with-maasai.html</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Could you repeat that?&amp;rdquo; I asked.
&amp;ldquo;Born during the rains from Sangok,&amp;rdquo; he said.
He was taller than me but not so tall as to undeniably fit the bill as a typical Masai; anywhere between 35 and 40 years of age. He wore a traditional Masai outfit that betrayed a bit of its costume nature thanks to being prim, proper and perhaps ironed out. A day before that, during the drive here I had seen a few Masai villagers who walked the road, with dust that refused to part with their faces and clothes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bryce : A Living Planetarium</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/bryce-a-living-planetarium.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2023 05:08:07 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/bryce-a-living-planetarium.html</guid>
      <description>It was not easy to comprehend the uniqueness of what was going on. There he was, a seemingly ordinary Park Ranger as he stood with his hands inside the pockets of his jacket to beat the chill of the night while he gave us a short lecture on what we were about to do and witness. I looked around. We were twenty of us who had signed up for the event, standing around in a circle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bonding with Boda Boda driver over football</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/bonding-with-bodaboda-driver-over-football.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 21:59:40 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/bonding-with-bodaboda-driver-over-football.html</guid>
      <description>Leaving Bwindi Impenetrable rainforests was quite painful. Very soon we would be pushed from pristine rainforests to flatlands in no time, and it also meant dealing with more people. I took in my last sights and smells to the fullest - the starlit sky, the fresh cool mountain air and the huge dark shadows in the backdrop of the mountains that were not yet visible before day break. We had to leave at 6am, which meant most of the work, like packing up our tent, having a good cup of morning coffee and saying goodbyes to our hosts had to be done in the cold and in darkness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drive Through Ishasha</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/drive-through-ishasha.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 21:59:40 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/drive-through-ishasha.html</guid>
      <description>On the streets of the small town Kihiihi, we sat found an empty taxi and quickly boarded it. As we had the breakfast that we had packed from Bwindi, we saw that the shops were just starting to open. We saw them getting ready for the day by arranging their display pieces outside and cleaning the entrances. There were many people all dressed up and purposeful, walking in a single direction and very excited.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Camping by the Nile</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/camping-by-the-nile.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 21:57:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/camping-by-the-nile.html</guid>
      <description>After a nerve-wracking boda boda ride, we arrived at the gate of Nile River Explorers parched, exhausted and covered in mud. What I saw inside immediately lifted my mood; smiling faces, a bar overlooking the Nile and clean bathrooms. All I needed was a refreshing shower and a chilled beer. Both were readily available. Soon I found myself watching a group of macaques through my binoculars as I sipped beer at one of the river-front tables.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving With the Mail</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/moving-with-the-mail.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 21:56:24 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/moving-with-the-mail.html</guid>
      <description>I had read about the post bus: a bus service run by the postal department of Uganda. However, nothing that I had read would prepare us for what we were about to go through. At 4:30am, lugging our heavy backpacks, we undertook a short, yet scary walk through the roads of Kampala to reach the post office. In most parts of Uganda, especially in busy market areas of down-town Kampala, where we stayed, near the bus stand, we were afraid of getting mugged while walking in the darkness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Whirling Dervishes of Turkey</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/the-whirling-dervishes-of-turkey.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 21:52:04 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/the-whirling-dervishes-of-turkey.html</guid>
      <description>Istanbul&amp;rsquo;s reputation as a historical city with great culture and tradition was one of the reasons we decided to generously let it occupy a greater part of our Turkey trip. While reading about the culture, I came upon its Sufi tradition, known as the Mevlevi Order; inspired by &amp;ldquo;Mevlana&amp;rdquo; Rumi, the famous Islamic mystical poet and spiritual master. Sufism is a form of Islam which emphasizes the inward search for God through direct connect and promotes realization of God through love and music.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Volunteering for Food</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/volunteering-for-food.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 21:36:01 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/volunteering-for-food.html</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Why we chose Bunda, or should I say, why Bunda chose us?&amp;rdquo; our host Aysha spoke of her reason for choosing to make this sleepy village her home. I sat in front of her nervously, hoping that the voice was clearly recording and we would complete the interview in a single take. She was dressed up for the interview, had rehearsed the questions, but we chose to keep the interview itself spontaneous, impromptu and she was eager to get it right.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Land Border Crossing from Kenya to Tanzania</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/land-border-crossing-from-kenya-to-tanzania.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 21:31:49 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/land-border-crossing-from-kenya-to-tanzania.html</guid>
      <description>We left Kisii early in the morning, after a breakfast consisting of coffee and Mandazi. The Matatu stand was close to where we stayed and this gave us the advantage of walking right up to it with our backpacks. As expected, someone &amp;ldquo;fished&amp;rdquo; us and led us through the maze of Matatus parked to a specific one that said Kisii Direct. We had learned that &amp;ldquo;direct&amp;rdquo; means no changes/transfers midway. Then again, we knew enough by now - practical and experienced in this part of the world - that what they promised was not always what they delivered.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Nairobi to Narok</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/from-nairobi-to-narok.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 06:25:47 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/from-nairobi-to-narok.html</guid>
      <description>The notorious reputation of Matatus that I had gathered from various forums preceded their appearance. This made me look at each of them with horror, like they were assassins. When I saw them while crossing the street, I would jump and step back, holding my partner&amp;rsquo;s hand tightly, with my eyes shut, as though, they were on a mission to kill; as if they would, at any time, veer off the road, into the footpath and run me over.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anchorage to Seward</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/anchorage-to-seward.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 05:03:21 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/anchorage-to-seward.html</guid>
      <description>There is something about trains that the moment someone mentions them, I get goosebumps; my heart starts racing and invariably. It is my wish to travel through some of the historical routes across the world, some spanning across continents and some meandering through unbelievable landscapes. I am always wondering about the ingenuity of the engineers who imagined a railroad and made it a reality. I try to incorporate train journeys to cover parts of my travel wherever feasible and affordable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talkeetna : Alaskan Hinterland</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/talkeetna-alaskan-hinterland.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 03:25:04 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/talkeetna-alaskan-hinterland.html</guid>
      <description>As I walked the barely asphalted road that led us from the well wooded section that closely guarded our hideout into what was the active and colourful part of the town, I started realizing why I liked this place so much. For one, it was unlike the rest of the United States. There was an authentic small-town feel to it. Not the sterile and templated small-town that one gets used to in the U.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Turkish Bath at a Hamam, Istanbul</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/hamam-at-istanbul-turkey.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 19:55:03 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/hamam-at-istanbul-turkey.html</guid>
      <description>After having spent two months backpacking and camping, the idea of a nice hot Turkish bath seemed most desirable. Although I did not have a first hand experience about a Hamam, having read a few blogs about it, I felt I was bold enough to give it a try. Having been to Istanbul and not trying the Hamam was not acceptable for me. I kept putting it off for the first couple of days, with certain inhibitions getting the better of my cravings for a hot bath.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Staying in a cavehouse at Goreme, Cappadocia</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/goreme-cappadocia-homestay.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 19:32:07 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/goreme-cappadocia-homestay.html</guid>
      <description>Goreme was a beautiful town in a valley beyond the vast, brown mountains and large smooth rocks that resembled endless mounds of mud. That morning, we were transferred to a mini-bus after an overnight journey in a comfortable, large bus. We had got used to the efficiency of this country, and the general goodness of people, so we only had to step out of the bus and step into the smaller bus, without having to fuss about our luggages, which were perfectly tagged and transferred promptly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azaan at Sultanahmet, Istanbul</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/azaan-at-sultanahmet-istanbul.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 18:58:38 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/azaan-at-sultanahmet-istanbul.html</guid>
      <description>Walking the crowded streets of Sultanahmet late evening, I was trying to negotiate a road crossing, just as a tram passed the street. The wind was chill yet filled with the aroma of the food from the roadside restaurants. Just then, I heard the most melodious tune somewhere far that made me freeze. I just stood there mesmerized, holding on to every single sound that came out from this singer. The words &amp;ldquo;Allahu Akhbar&amp;rdquo;, probably heard several times in my lifetime, had never before sounded so beautiful, so profound.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A walk through Sinharaja Forest Reserve, Sri Lanka</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/sinharaja-forest-reserve-srilanka.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 19:33:32 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/sinharaja-forest-reserve-srilanka.html</guid>
      <description>I had imagined this tear-drop-shaped island country always to have been green; a green dot floating in the endless blue waters of the mighty Indian Ocean. I would like to believe that it was once covered with dense impenetrable tropical rainforests, with innumerable waterfalls and countless streams. It was perhaps my effort to recreate this lost experience, when I chose trekking through the Sinharaja Forest Reserve as one of my first experiences in Sri Lanka.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Glacier Tour, Seward, Alaska</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/glacier-tour-seward.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2021 12:22:51 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/glacier-tour-seward.html</guid>
      <description>A bald eagle swooped in very close to our boat as we set off. The sun was struggling to shine through the dense grey clouds that threatened to pour down anytime. To be sailing off into the icy cold waters of the Pacific, with limited visibility, in the hope of seeing some glaciers, started to seem a bit ambitious. The misty cold morning confined most of us to the cozy interior of the boat, with little to look forward to other than this bald eagle and a friendly otter that did not seem to mind either our boat or the ice cold water.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Staying in a remote East Ugandan Village, Africa</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/homestay-experience-bududa.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2020 11:16:15 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/homestay-experience-bududa.html</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Is it true that women are burnt alive for dowry in India?&amp;rdquo; Mai asked with fear in her eyes and a palm covering her mouth. She did not mean to offend me. The innocence in her voice and her genuine concern for her sisters in India made me offer a simple, plain answer. &amp;ldquo;Yes, it does happen even now in some villages&amp;rdquo; I tried to calm her down. &amp;ldquo;I heard that in India women have to pay dowry money?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whale Watching at Mirissa, Sri Lanka</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/whale-watching-lanka.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 17:13:01 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/whale-watching-lanka.html</guid>
      <description>This was nothing close to what I had imagined. The boat was rather small. The waves were menacingly rough, and threatened to throw the boat off balance at the slightest opportunity. There were about 20 people on the boat, most of them in various stages of sea sickness. The lucky ones, like myself, who were miraculously unaffected by the rough sea, were on the deck with our eyes glued to the waters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Live Music Bar at Goreme, Cappadocia, Turkey</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/live-music-bar-goreme.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 16:57:03 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/live-music-bar-goreme.html</guid>
      <description>The cold air was broken by the white trail of warm breath as I walked into the night. The bar was just a block away from where we stayed. The tables were only beginning to be occupied. We asked for a table for two, ordered some Raki that came with some soft bread and dips. The lights were dim and created a warm and cozy atmosphere. Everyone were dressed in party-wear, colourful, resplendent with makeup and jewellery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Camping next to Savage river, Denali National Park</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/camping-at-savage-river.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 10:32:42 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/camping-at-savage-river.html</guid>
      <description>The weather was perfect when we entered Denali National Park. The sun was bright and our bus made a special stop on the way just for us to get a view of the majestic mountain Denali because it is not everyday that she presents herself in such glory. I have heard about the disappointment some people face when they spend two days at the National Park but fail to get a glimpse of the mountain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Denali at her raw best</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/denali-at-her-raw-best.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 10:17:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/denali-at-her-raw-best.html</guid>
      <description>Sitting in the park bus, I felt as though we were on a private tour of Denali National Park, just 4 of us, and our guide cum driver, Nick. It was to be the last trip for the day. That afternoon the entire Denali range was covered by thick clouds, it had started to get dark. Our chances of spotting wildlife also diminished with the daylight. With the rain looming in the horizon, we almost had the entire park for ourselves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An unforgettable encounter with our closest cousin</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/our-closest-cousin.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2019 19:17:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/our-closest-cousin.html</guid>
      <description>It was unmistakably the most beautiful place we would be staying in our entire trip. I could spend hours just looking at the mountains, and the rainforests and never cease to be amazed by their existence, being drawn into them further and further with every passing moment. I could be lost momentarily in mundane tasks like eating or washing clothes or fussing about the ants but the presence of the mountains constantly pulls me into a trance every now and then.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A walk through Stone Town, Zanzibar</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/stonetown-zanzibar.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 19:02:15 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/stonetown-zanzibar.html</guid>
      <description>Just outside, you find yourself in a typical African town, with people getting about their routine work. There is traffic, pollution, vehicles honking, hawkers selling everything from bread, fruits, vegetables, newspaper to bags, shoes, clothes and people haggling for a good bargain; burqa clad school girls gossiping in small groups, giggling, waiting for their bus; high school boys trying to look like grown up men, wearing their traditional cap and gown, but their their school bags giving them away.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
