<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>February on Yﾄ》rﾄ［aya</title>
    <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/month/february.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in February on Yﾄ》rﾄ［aya</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 06:54:19 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/month/february/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Work Hard Beach Soft</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/work-hard-beach-soft.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2023 06:54:19 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/work-hard-beach-soft.html</guid>
      <description>As we drove farther to the west, the landscape changed from the usual staple of large buildings with their even-larger parking lots, to one, that in appearance, had a little more of what I conjure up in my mind whenever I come across the word &amp;lsquo;California&amp;rsquo;. A friend of mine had once told me I&amp;rsquo;d fit right in because I was a tree-hugger. In the literal sense of that term, at least, this seemed the most likely possibility as I witnessed here some of the largest, tallest and oldest redwood trees; trees whose circumference would have made me look like an insect hanging on to the bark when attempting to hug one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Land Border Crossing From Kenya to Uganda</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/land-border-crossing-from-kenya-to-uganda.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 06:07:37 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/land-border-crossing-from-kenya-to-uganda.html</guid>
      <description>They say, there is always a first time for everything. I remember some of my firsts and not all of them are pleasant ones. As the bus pulled up into a nondescript corner of the street and the conductor announced that we had arrived, I felt another first; anxious thoughts about the next few minutes. The last few hours were spent in the knowledge of what we were up to but anxiety had not taken over due to the novelty of what was on offer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Walking the Maara With the Masai</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/walking-the-maara-with-maasai.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 06:50:06 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/walking-the-maara-with-maasai.html</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Could you repeat that?&amp;rdquo; I asked.
&amp;ldquo;Born during the rains from Sangok,&amp;rdquo; he said.
He was taller than me but not so tall as to undeniably fit the bill as a typical Masai; anywhere between 35 and 40 years of age. He wore a traditional Masai outfit that betrayed a bit of its costume nature thanks to being prim, proper and perhaps ironed out. A day before that, during the drive here I had seen a few Masai villagers who walked the road, with dust that refused to part with their faces and clothes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bonding with Boda Boda driver over football</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/bonding-with-bodaboda-driver-over-football.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 21:59:40 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/bonding-with-bodaboda-driver-over-football.html</guid>
      <description>Leaving Bwindi Impenetrable rainforests was quite painful. Very soon we would be pushed from pristine rainforests to flatlands in no time, and it also meant dealing with more people. I took in my last sights and smells to the fullest - the starlit sky, the fresh cool mountain air and the huge dark shadows in the backdrop of the mountains that were not yet visible before day break. We had to leave at 6am, which meant most of the work, like packing up our tent, having a good cup of morning coffee and saying goodbyes to our hosts had to be done in the cold and in darkness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drive Through Ishasha</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/drive-through-ishasha.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 21:59:40 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/drive-through-ishasha.html</guid>
      <description>On the streets of the small town Kihiihi, we sat found an empty taxi and quickly boarded it. As we had the breakfast that we had packed from Bwindi, we saw that the shops were just starting to open. We saw them getting ready for the day by arranging their display pieces outside and cleaning the entrances. There were many people all dressed up and purposeful, walking in a single direction and very excited.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Camping by the Nile</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/camping-by-the-nile.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 21:57:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/camping-by-the-nile.html</guid>
      <description>After a nerve-wracking boda boda ride, we arrived at the gate of Nile River Explorers parched, exhausted and covered in mud. What I saw inside immediately lifted my mood; smiling faces, a bar overlooking the Nile and clean bathrooms. All I needed was a refreshing shower and a chilled beer. Both were readily available. Soon I found myself watching a group of macaques through my binoculars as I sipped beer at one of the river-front tables.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving With the Mail</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/moving-with-the-mail.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 21:56:24 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/moving-with-the-mail.html</guid>
      <description>I had read about the post bus: a bus service run by the postal department of Uganda. However, nothing that I had read would prepare us for what we were about to go through. At 4:30am, lugging our heavy backpacks, we undertook a short, yet scary walk through the roads of Kampala to reach the post office. In most parts of Uganda, especially in busy market areas of down-town Kampala, where we stayed, near the bus stand, we were afraid of getting mugged while walking in the darkness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Nairobi to Narok</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/from-nairobi-to-narok.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 06:25:47 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/from-nairobi-to-narok.html</guid>
      <description>The notorious reputation of Matatus that I had gathered from various forums preceded their appearance. This made me look at each of them with horror, like they were assassins. When I saw them while crossing the street, I would jump and step back, holding my partner&amp;rsquo;s hand tightly, with my eyes shut, as though, they were on a mission to kill; as if they would, at any time, veer off the road, into the footpath and run me over.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Staying in a remote East Ugandan Village, Africa</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/homestay-experience-bududa.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2020 11:16:15 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/homestay-experience-bududa.html</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Is it true that women are burnt alive for dowry in India?&amp;rdquo; Mai asked with fear in her eyes and a palm covering her mouth. She did not mean to offend me. The innocence in her voice and her genuine concern for her sisters in India made me offer a simple, plain answer. &amp;ldquo;Yes, it does happen even now in some villages&amp;rdquo; I tried to calm her down. &amp;ldquo;I heard that in India women have to pay dowry money?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An unforgettable encounter with our closest cousin</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/our-closest-cousin.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2019 19:17:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/our-closest-cousin.html</guid>
      <description>It was unmistakably the most beautiful place we would be staying in our entire trip. I could spend hours just looking at the mountains, and the rainforests and never cease to be amazed by their existence, being drawn into them further and further with every passing moment. I could be lost momentarily in mundane tasks like eating or washing clothes or fussing about the ants but the presence of the mountains constantly pulls me into a trance every now and then.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
