<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>River on Yﾄ》rﾄ［aya</title>
    <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/types/river.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in River on Yﾄ》rﾄ［aya</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 05:06:19 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/types/river/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Amazon and its Tributaries</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/the-amazon-and-its-tributaries.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 05:06:19 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/the-amazon-and-its-tributaries.html</guid>
      <description>It was exactly how I had imagined it; perhaps better than that, because I remember sitting on that boat spellbound and self-aware that I had gone very quiet. The boat was navigating through the Maranon river in whose waters reflected the rising sun. The reflection moved ahead as we did ever so slowly, unhurried by the seeming speed that was implied by the engine itself which was the only thing I can remember as noise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homes on Stilts in the Amazon</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/homes-on-stilts-in-the-amazon.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 05:41:54 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/homes-on-stilts-in-the-amazon.html</guid>
      <description>The bare-bones dwelling on stilts appeared like creatures that could discreetly shy away inland when the river asserts its rights annually. I was excited like never before to step inside, as Jana (pronounced Yaana) explained the basics to us. Jana was a volunteer with the organization. She spoke with passion about the project; its mission and accomplishments. But mainly, she paused to speak about the mosquitoes when I inquired. I did not have an original inquiry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Camping by the Nile</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/camping-by-the-nile.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 21:57:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/camping-by-the-nile.html</guid>
      <description>After a nerve-wracking boda boda ride, we arrived at the gate of Nile River Explorers parched, exhausted and covered in mud. What I saw inside immediately lifted my mood; smiling faces, a bar overlooking the Nile and clean bathrooms. All I needed was a refreshing shower and a chilled beer. Both were readily available. Soon I found myself watching a group of macaques through my binoculars as I sipped beer at one of the river-front tables.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We still have not seen the Tapir</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/we-still-have-not-seen-the-tapir.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 05:11:21 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/we-still-have-not-seen-the-tapir.html</guid>
      <description>At 4am, I could see the faint light in the other tents. Braving the cold and in complete darkness with the help of a flash-light, I managed to crawl out of mine. The moonless sky shone with a million stars. Wearing our rubber boots our team of four started walking towards the forest. The cicadas seemed to cheer us on and follow us into the darkness as we moved in. The eerie ambience was complemented by a million other insects that were probably protesting as we walked through the maze of branches and roots.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talkeetna : Alaskan Hinterland</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/talkeetna-alaskan-hinterland.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 03:25:04 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/talkeetna-alaskan-hinterland.html</guid>
      <description>As I walked the barely asphalted road that led us from the well wooded section that closely guarded our hideout into what was the active and colourful part of the town, I started realizing why I liked this place so much. For one, it was unlike the rest of the United States. There was an authentic small-town feel to it. Not the sterile and templated small-town that one gets used to in the U.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Camping next to Savage river, Denali National Park</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/camping-at-savage-river.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 10:32:42 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/camping-at-savage-river.html</guid>
      <description>The weather was perfect when we entered Denali National Park. The sun was bright and our bus made a special stop on the way just for us to get a view of the majestic mountain Denali because it is not everyday that she presents herself in such glory. I have heard about the disappointment some people face when they spend two days at the National Park but fail to get a glimpse of the mountain.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
