<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bolivia on Yﾄ》rﾄ［aya</title>
    <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/countries/bolivia.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bolivia on Yﾄ》rﾄ［aya</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 10:59:40 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/countries/bolivia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Amazonian Community of San Jose de Uchupiamonas</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/amazonian-community-of-san-jose-de-uchupiamonas.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 10:59:40 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/amazonian-community-of-san-jose-de-uchupiamonas.html</guid>
      <description>Very soon, the driver of our car sounded excited and stopped the car by the side of the road. Soon, we were all looking in the direction where he was looking. He had spotted some furry animals; extremely cute rodents. 5 or 6 young ones of the Capybara. The mother was nearby, quite large in comparison. Soon she and her flock disappeared into a burrow. This was our first sighting of Capybaras and we were extremely happy to see them from so near, just by the side of the road.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lounge-birding at Sadiri lodge</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/lounge-birding-at-sadiri-lodge.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 05:24:31 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/lounge-birding-at-sadiri-lodge.html</guid>
      <description>We got a glimpse of what we would experience after 3 days when we stepped into Sadiri Lodge briefly to put away some our clothes that we wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be needing during the camping. The lodge was located on a hill, the steep slope of which was lined with a stone-pitched stairway that we arduously climbed. The entrance of the prominent looking building, completely built of wood, led to the dining hall with a large balcony overlooking the dramatic mountain ranges of Amazon rainforests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Birdwatching in the Bolivian Amazon</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/amazing-birds-of-amazon.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 05:17:41 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/amazing-birds-of-amazon.html</guid>
      <description>If I had one favourite species, which bird would I really like to see? That was the question posed to me by Ricardo, our guide. My ambitious yet truthful answer to his question was, the Harpy&amp;rsquo;s Eagle. Ricardo smiled and I returned it. But we weren&amp;rsquo;t kidding each other. The bird watching experience here in the Amazon was supposed to be bit different, and by different, I mean very challenging when compared to what I had experienced up until then, back home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We still have not seen the Tapir</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/we-still-have-not-seen-the-tapir.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 05:11:21 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/we-still-have-not-seen-the-tapir.html</guid>
      <description>At 4am, I could see the faint light in the other tents. Braving the cold and in complete darkness with the help of a flash-light, I managed to crawl out of mine. The moonless sky shone with a million stars. Wearing our rubber boots our team of four started walking towards the forest. The cicadas seemed to cheer us on and follow us into the darkness as we moved in. The eerie ambience was complemented by a million other insects that were probably protesting as we walked through the maze of branches and roots.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
