<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>August on Yﾄ》rﾄ［aya</title>
    <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/month/august.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in August on Yﾄ》rﾄ［aya</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 17:00:59 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/month/august/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>From the Bolivian Highlands of La Paz, to Copacabana</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/bus-ride-to-copacabana.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 17:00:59 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/bus-ride-to-copacabana.html</guid>
      <description>There are many ways to travel from La Paz, Bolivia to Cusco, Peru. What we chose to do was use the services of Bolivia Hop which is a hop-on-hop-off bus service that also had an optional stopover at Copacabana. These pictures tell the story of the first leg of that journey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High Altitude Capital City, La Paz, Bolivia</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/high-altitude-capital-city-la-paz.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 17:00:59 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/high-altitude-capital-city-la-paz.html</guid>
      <description>La Paz, the highest capital city in the world. What does it feel like? We knew very little, because we mostly used La Paz as a hop-off point for our trip to other seductive corners of Bolivia, but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t a wonder that we could relegate to the back-burner for long. So off we went on a short walk around the city to find out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Amazonian Community of San Jose de Uchupiamonas</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/amazonian-community-of-san-jose-de-uchupiamonas.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 10:59:40 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/amazonian-community-of-san-jose-de-uchupiamonas.html</guid>
      <description>Very soon, the driver of our car sounded excited and stopped the car by the side of the road. Soon, we were all looking in the direction where he was looking. He had spotted some furry animals; extremely cute rodents. 5 or 6 young ones of the Capybara. The mother was nearby, quite large in comparison. Soon she and her flock disappeared into a burrow. This was our first sighting of Capybaras and we were extremely happy to see them from so near, just by the side of the road.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Babbling on a clothesline</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/babbling-on-a-clothesline.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 06:46:36 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/babbling-on-a-clothesline.html</guid>
      <description>A wet babbler jumped up on a clothesline under a shelter to escape the downpour. A moment ago she was busy pecking on the wet ground in search of insects and worms. With no sunshine the entire morning, birds were not at their chirpy best, they must be going through their mood swings too! The overcast skies covered everything in dull grey. The babblers still needed to look for their food.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It is raining in Kerala!</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/rains-kerala.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 06:39:29 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/rains-kerala.html</guid>
      <description>The leaves are bright green of various shades, all washed and cleaned. Everything turns green - the plants, trees, walls, the floor, there is fresh growth all around. The trees and plants have all drank to their fill and stored up water for the next season. The soil has soaked up water and is saturated. Small streams of brown water are making their way through previously non-existent routes to lower lands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trip to a Bolivian Consulate</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/trip-to-a-bolivian-consulate.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 05:30:10 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/trip-to-a-bolivian-consulate.html</guid>
      <description>Most of the tourists who land at the Calama Airport in Northern Chile have but one purpose which is to book a direct taxi to their real destination, San Pedro de Atacama, the jewel of the Atacama desert, a picturesque town that is tailored around tourism. Calama, on the other hand is a mining town visited by workers - both short and long term - and people who have some business connected to mining.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lounge-birding at Sadiri lodge</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/lounge-birding-at-sadiri-lodge.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 05:24:31 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/lounge-birding-at-sadiri-lodge.html</guid>
      <description>We got a glimpse of what we would experience after 3 days when we stepped into Sadiri Lodge briefly to put away some our clothes that we wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be needing during the camping. The lodge was located on a hill, the steep slope of which was lined with a stone-pitched stairway that we arduously climbed. The entrance of the prominent looking building, completely built of wood, led to the dining hall with a large balcony overlooking the dramatic mountain ranges of Amazon rainforests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Birdwatching in the Bolivian Amazon</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/amazing-birds-of-amazon.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 05:17:41 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/amazing-birds-of-amazon.html</guid>
      <description>If I had one favourite species, which bird would I really like to see? That was the question posed to me by Ricardo, our guide. My ambitious yet truthful answer to his question was, the Harpy&amp;rsquo;s Eagle. Ricardo smiled and I returned it. But we weren&amp;rsquo;t kidding each other. The bird watching experience here in the Amazon was supposed to be bit different, and by different, I mean very challenging when compared to what I had experienced up until then, back home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We still have not seen the Tapir</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/we-still-have-not-seen-the-tapir.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 05:11:21 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/we-still-have-not-seen-the-tapir.html</guid>
      <description>At 4am, I could see the faint light in the other tents. Braving the cold and in complete darkness with the help of a flash-light, I managed to crawl out of mine. The moonless sky shone with a million stars. Wearing our rubber boots our team of four started walking towards the forest. The cicadas seemed to cheer us on and follow us into the darkness as we moved in. The eerie ambience was complemented by a million other insects that were probably protesting as we walked through the maze of branches and roots.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anchorage to Seward</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/anchorage-to-seward.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 05:03:21 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/anchorage-to-seward.html</guid>
      <description>There is something about trains that the moment someone mentions them, I get goosebumps; my heart starts racing and invariably. It is my wish to travel through some of the historical routes across the world, some spanning across continents and some meandering through unbelievable landscapes. I am always wondering about the ingenuity of the engineers who imagined a railroad and made it a reality. I try to incorporate train journeys to cover parts of my travel wherever feasible and affordable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talkeetna : Alaskan Hinterland</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/talkeetna-alaskan-hinterland.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 03:25:04 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/talkeetna-alaskan-hinterland.html</guid>
      <description>As I walked the barely asphalted road that led us from the well wooded section that closely guarded our hideout into what was the active and colourful part of the town, I started realizing why I liked this place so much. For one, it was unlike the rest of the United States. There was an authentic small-town feel to it. Not the sterile and templated small-town that one gets used to in the U.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Glacier Tour, Seward, Alaska</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/glacier-tour-seward.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2021 12:22:51 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/glacier-tour-seward.html</guid>
      <description>A bald eagle swooped in very close to our boat as we set off. The sun was struggling to shine through the dense grey clouds that threatened to pour down anytime. To be sailing off into the icy cold waters of the Pacific, with limited visibility, in the hope of seeing some glaciers, started to seem a bit ambitious. The misty cold morning confined most of us to the cozy interior of the boat, with little to look forward to other than this bald eagle and a friendly otter that did not seem to mind either our boat or the ice cold water.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wildlife Viewing in Denali National Park</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/wildlife-viewing-denali.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2020 16:16:02 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/wildlife-viewing-denali.html</guid>
      <description>We got onto the transit bus to Wonder Lake, one of the farthest camp-grounds inside the Denali National park. Springtime being good tourist season, the bus was full and we managed to occupy the last second row. With my camera ready, I glued my eyes to the window of the bus, carefully scanning the vast landscape for any movement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Camping next to Savage river, Denali National Park</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/camping-at-savage-river.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 10:32:42 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/camping-at-savage-river.html</guid>
      <description>The weather was perfect when we entered Denali National Park. The sun was bright and our bus made a special stop on the way just for us to get a view of the majestic mountain Denali because it is not everyday that she presents herself in such glory. I have heard about the disappointment some people face when they spend two days at the National Park but fail to get a glimpse of the mountain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Denali at her raw best</title>
      <link>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/denali-at-her-raw-best.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 10:17:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yatramaya.hoatz.in/experiences/denali-at-her-raw-best.html</guid>
      <description>Sitting in the park bus, I felt as though we were on a private tour of Denali National Park, just 4 of us, and our guide cum driver, Nick. It was to be the last trip for the day. That afternoon the entire Denali range was covered by thick clouds, it had started to get dark. Our chances of spotting wildlife also diminished with the daylight. With the rain looming in the horizon, we almost had the entire park for ourselves.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
